I apologize for the delay.
But I'm here now.
What's up, guys?
And girls?
Man, oh man.
Belts are amazing.
I think I actually dreamt about belts.
But I'm not 100% sure.
Because I woke up and I was like, wait a minute, did I just dream about factory stuff?
I think I did.
But like, I'm not 100%.
It felt like it.
I didn't quite remember, you know, half-remembered dream and all that.
We're gonna make so many things with belts.
Probably my favorite thing in Create so far.
That and the digging machine.
What happened for the second half of last stream?
Winning.
Happened.
It was pure, unadulterated win.
It was incredible.
Stop only using the 8th slot to level me.
You know?
I do realize that I do that.
And I don't know how to fix it.
Let me ask you something.
How would you do it?
What would you do?
What are you guys doing?
Are you putting everything you need on separate hotkeys?
And then just pressing 1, 2, 3, 4, 5?
That's horrible.
Because you don't know what you'll need.
Like, when I go to the store, you know, I know I need one or two things.
I bring them back home.
I never go to the store with like 10 things on a recipe.
Or a, uh...
What do you call it?
A, um...
A buying list.
You know?
I go to the store every day to get one or two items.
Scroll wheel?
Uh...
Yeah, okay.
I...
It's just not very intuitive for me.
Like, I think I just don't really gel with the way the hotbar works in Minecraft.
And my brain.
I mean, there's nothing wrong with it.
It's just that I don't really gel with it, you know?
It's not comfortable.
But, you know, I make it work.
It's not that, uh, you know...
Okay, I use the 8th bar or the 8th slot quite a bit.
But it's not like a big deal.
I'm fine with it.
You sound like Onipixel?
That sounds German to me.
Is that a German guy?
That means without a pixel.
Or no pixel.
Oh, well, there you go.
So it is German.
Are you saying I sound German?
Wait, does he also only use the 8th slot?
Oh, he does?
Okay, well, there you go, guys.
I'm not the only one.
It's normal.
There's something magical about the 8th slot.
Why no Sims Voughts?
Because I kind of stopped playing Sims right now since I got addicted to Minecraft again.
The next time I stream Sims, it's going to be Sims 2.
We're going to continue on in the series.
No, but you sound German.
I actually did watch some clips from German, guys.
Because everyone was talking about it ever since the first season, so...
I, you know, I stumbled over some of the clips from him.
He's kind of funny, though.
I see why you guys love him.
But I wouldn't say I sound like him.
Then again, I haven't watched that much of him, but yeah.
He seems kind of funny.
I like his face.
How long do you think this series will last?
I have no idea.
Until I don't have fun anymore.
Until I don't want to play anymore.
Right now, I'm in...
I'm hardcore addicted, though.
So it's going to last for a while longer.
He's handsome.
He is handsome!
If I was as handsome as German, I would probably put on the webcam, too.
I saw a clip of him.
Speaking of webcam, where...
When he turns his webcam on...
He's briefly naked.
And then it comes back.
Like, what the hell is that?
That made me laugh.
That is quite funny.
I don't know if you've seen that clip.
Or, like, he's not naked.
He just...
I think he doesn't have a shirt on or something.
And it's just like...
What kind of a...
Technical error is that?
That makes you look naked, you know?
His camera saved the last frame of when it was on.
Oh!
I see.
I guess that explains it.
I think it's your cadence of speaking more than the voice that people relate to German.
Really?
That's weird.
He's American, right?
I guess I would say I have sort of an American accent because I've been influenced by movies.
I definitely don't have a British accent.
But yeah, I...
I...
When I speak English, it's definitely American-inspired.
Like, I don't say arrivederci.
I say arrivederci, you know?
That's more natural to me.
I saw some chats that the cogs changed.
Wait, uh...
What do you mean?
Which cogs changed?
Say bowl of water.
Bowl of water.
Easy.
But you can say it fast.
Bowl of water.
Cogs, not...
Okay, listen.
I can...
I can say the difference.
There's cogs...
And cogs.
I'm saying it the right way.
I'm saying cogs.
You guys are just...
Hearing what you wanna hear.
You know?
So, you know...
Conclude whatever you will from that.
I'd say it's on you, not me.
You're the one who has a dirty mind.
Not me.
My mind is pristine.
It's clean.
Well, not always.
I do...
I do make some jokes here and there that...
Are somewhat lewd, but...
That's because I have a simple mind and I appreciate simple jokes.
Also, I'm 12 years old.
Mentally.
Clean as a cog.
Oh, that was...
That was actually super clean the way I just said that.
That was...
That was no doubt I said cog.
Maybe I'll just say cog from now on to not be mistaken, you know?
You cannot mistake that for the other word.
I wish the game would just call them gears so I can be reminded of that.
Because every time I search for the cog, you know?
I get reminded of it.
The cog.
Say coughing like Dutch people.
Uh...
I don't know.
I don't know what Dutch people sound like when they say cough.
Okay.
It's time to play some Minecraft.
Are you ready?
Wait, you can't hear?
Yo, you can hear something.
Also, try pixel junk shooter.
What the hell?
Let's go.
Oh, man.
I'm so excited.
Wait, why am I here?
I could have sworn I was at my...
Okay, maybe I just locked out here, I guess.
Fine.
Oh, my...
Wait, is that normal that I have this much range to open the chest?
Look at that.
I'm standing here.
That feels crazy.
That's a long range.
I feel like that's not normal.
But maybe I'm just not remembering right.
Okay.
I think today we're definitely gonna follow the...
So, I did actually write this list last time as a joke.
But I'm actually kind of serious about it.
These are some of the things that I thought about.
This one in particular...
We have to do.
We gotta make the path everywhere.
We have to make a path now that goes towards the factory.
Now, obviously, the factory is not done yet.
It's just the humble beginnings of a great future.
But, you know.
For now...
Oh, why is this not green anymore?
That's funny.
So, when you do this, it becomes green.
And then when you click on it, it doesn't.
Ah, and it's because I have it selected.
Okay, I see.
Cool.
Also, weird that this icon is the close icon.
It's like two arrows down.
That, to me, sounds like I'm scrolling.
This should be an X.
Terrible UX design.
Just kidding.
That's fine.
Poppy, why are you doing in there?
You shouldn't be in there.
Yeah, this windmill needs to be on top of the house.
100%.
Otherwise, it's not real.
That windmill right there...
isn't real.
I forgot how the quote goes.
There was this lady on a plane...
who was saying that someone wasn't real.
And I have been thinking about that lately.
Quite a bit.
Um, I don't know why.
It's stuck with me.
There's something quite scary about it, you know.
What if she did see something?
Antisite is in here.
Uh, string.
That is a miscellaneous...
Man, I nailed that first try.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, that's fine.
Spider eye.
Get in there.
The wrench is kind of essential.
Today, I'm going to use my toolbox more.
And, guys, I promise...
today, I will utilize...
all of my slots in the hotbar.
It will not be a...
eighth slotted...
Wait.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
Yeah, this is the eighth one I have right now.
There's nine in total.
I will use every single slot.
You'll see.
See?
Make a tree chopper at the top of the mountain.
Great!
Because we have, like, a tree situation...
where it goes down...
into the roots...
and the roots become little trees, too.
And all of those things...
turn into wood-based items...
on the output.
You see what I mean?
Pint point...
power...
sorusus...
where we need it.
Also, look for potential other sources of power.
Fission.
I don't think this is real.
But who knows?
Dig for more diorite and get more wood.
True!
We gotta do that.
So that means...
we gotta get the saw.
But hold on.
Maybe I should think about what to do first.
Right now, the success is actually kinda staggering.
If I can put it like that.
Because we have a working factory...
and it's producing floors.
And I'm going to use those.
Maybe I'll do it now.
Oh my god.
Oh, there's two of them!
What the?
Come here!
Give me your pearls!
Dude, maybe we killed a dragon today.
Why are they...
Oh!
Wait, what?
I'm not safe here!
I'm dying!
Run to the tree!
I'm dead.
Holy shit, dude!
Fucking crisis management expert right here.
CME.
Not to be confused with CMB, which is the cosmic microwave background.
That's a different thing.
Sleep, dude.
Holy crap.
Oh my god!
Don't hit me.
Wow.
Why is things so hectic right now?
Out of nowhere.
I just locked into the game, and already I'm being tested like this.
I don't appreciate it.
But, you know, on the other hand, it's a good wake-up call, you know?
Now I'm in the game.
There's no way to avoid it.
Okay, let's fill this hole up.
Nothing happened here.
Nothing to see.
Also, now the potatoes are really starting to show their inadequacy.
I need to eat at least 9,000 potatoes just to recover my health, which is a tragedy.
Steak is the way forward.
I guess we'll fix these crimes.
Also, I have no idea where my saw is.
It wasn't in the create chest.
Okay, fill this up.
Watch it.
Look at this!
I do wish it had a little sound when it went through, you know?
But I get it.
It's Minecraft.
You don't want to be overwhelmed by sounds in a game that is otherwise very silent.
Wait, it's actually working.
Oh, I have enough input here.
Nice.
43 andesite casings.
I can't stop looking at it.
Look at that!
Heh.
Fråda vack, fråda vack, fråda vack!
Lovely.
Lovely, lovely.
This is kind of ugly, though.
I feel like we can make that better.
But this is just a prototype.
And it's a beautiful one.
We shall expand the factory today to make other items.
But, uh, where am I limited right now?
So it's wood for sure.
And, let me see.
Oh, diorite.
We need diorite.
Yeah, we don't have enough of that.
Actually, we kind of have a lot.
So these two get turned into andesite.
Ah, we need zinc.
Yeah.
Zinc ingots or iron ingots.
See, we're actually out of...
Yeah, we can't do it anymore.
That's what we need.
So, we need the digging machine, right?
And the digging machine we have...
at home.
Somewhere.
Let me see what's in here.
Andesite.
Actually, grab those.
Um...
Do I need any of this?
Oh, we have these?
Let's put that in the box.
Oh, you bastard.
We don't discriminate on wood types here.
Anything gets...
cut.
My shield is needed.
Don't know where I put it.
Maybe over here.
Guys, today I'm gonna make a train.
I've been thinking about trains.
We gotta do it.
Um...
Because, think about it.
We make a train...
after we make tunnels.
It's actually perfect.
Wait, what was I looking for?
So we have the crank here.
Oh, the saw is right there!
It's being used, of course.
Right.
Makes sense.
I also need to stock up on standard exploration items, like torches and stuff.
Yeah, I don't need any of this right now.
That's good.
Wait, what's my shield in there?
No.
Okay.
Let's go back.
We're gonna go on an exploration trip.
Where we also dig.
We're gonna be digging.
We're gonna be mining.
And...
chopping.
And bringing home the bacon.
Because remember, we can essentially carry infinite items.
Now that we can...
put a contraption in our pocket.
It is crazy.
I need...
No.
What did I need?
I need to make a new saw.
Okay.
Oh, I don't have any iron.
This is actually such a problem.
We should go collect some, just to have the basics ready.
Yeah.
What about coal?
Oh, nice.
We got an iron there.
Is that enough?
No.
Did we really not...
Ah, there we go.
Coal.
Here.
64 torches.
I'm gonna leave six at home.
There.
Equipment is looking good.
A shield, of course.
This one is almost dead, so we can't use that.
Planks.
Um, let's use these for that.
Also, today I'm gonna take it easy.
I'm going to pretend like I am on some kind of medication.
That allows me to focus.
I'm not, but I'm gonna pretend I am.
I wish I had it.
Um, bucket here.
Shield.
Let's put that there.
Also, I'm gonna use this andesite alloy right now, just to get a preview.
Are you ready?
Let's preview this room.
Dude, it's looking great already.
Oh my god, it's looking good!
Tell me this isn't amazing.
Uh, that one too.
Oh, I ran out already.
Damn, we need a lot.
Okay.
Well, it was a start.
This clipboard.
Is anything important on that?
I feel like this clipboard should be back at the factory back there.
Let's put that there for now.
Same with the wrench.
No, wrench come with me because I need to transport the contraption.
Speaking of, it's right here.
So, for that one, we also need rails.
I'm going to empty this, I think.
Because we do need to fill this up on the way.
Oh wait, there was a way to do this fast.
Hold on, let me see if I remember.
Okay, I'm actually gonna...
Guys, I'm gonna ask you...
What is the word?
What is the safe word?
I forgot already.
Rotund!
What?
What did I have to do to transfer all of the cobblestone to the chest up here?
I discovered it once, I forgot.
Hold on, I have to alt-tap to see you guys.
What is it?
Hold, shift, and double-click...
I feel like I just did that.
Hold on.
Hold, shift, double-click.
It's just transferring this, though.
Oh, oh, there it is, there it is.
Ah, hold on.
Let me see.
So I want to transfer all the cobblestone over, so I click this.
Hold, shift.
There we go.
Okay.
Nice.
So watch, I can do this now.
Yeah.
Oh, very nice.
Let's see if I can start implementing that properly.
Okay.
Rotten Flesh is miscellaneous for sure.
Man, we also don't even have any proper enchants yet.
I'm almost level 30.
I think before I go on an expedition where I could potentially die, I should become level 30.
So that I can enchant my bow.
So, this needs to happen first.
Yep.
We're going to the nether real quick.
And the pearls go in here.
I have eight now.
I think I need 12 to go into the portal.
Oh, and we need to make this saw now.
Oh, we can't make that yet, right.
Okay, super glue is gonna go in here.
Or maybe I bring it with me because we're doing the contraption stuff, but that's not happening yet.
Let me prepare this folder, I should say, right there with the stuff we need on this trip.
Not that one.
Let's put this on a wall here.
This comes with me, of course.
Wait, I can also make more toolboxes, I guess.
Wait a sec.
Right?
Can I not?
Chest, wheel, leather, and golden sheet.
Chest, wheel,
leather, and chest.
Oh no, wait.
Some stuff is back here, I think.
Let me take this.
Maybe I can't make more toolboxes, actually.
I was about to say, that sounds a little too broken, but then again, then we have the contraption moving with, like, infinite items.
So, I don't know.
Maybe it's gonna work, you know?
Not a big deal.
Oh, fuck.
One wheel, and then we needed one chest.
Can I make a different color?
Wait a second.
So, you can have multiple toolboxes, confirmed.
But wait a sec.
I kind of want to color this if I can, because it says brown toolbox.
Sounds to me like you can probably make different ones.
Let me actually see if I can search for it.
It doesn't say...
I'm just gonna try and combine it with color, naively, and see what happens.
I must have some color.
White dye.
Let's try this.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
Oops.
In.
There you go.
Easy.
Put that back in.
The white toolbox is going to be...
like, mining stuff.
You know, like, oars and all that.
The brown one is...
a classic tool...
tool box needs to be red.
You know the classic one that you have, uh...
you have your food inside, and you go work in a house or whatever?
Like a contractor?
Yeah, that needs to be red, for sure.
So this one is just for...
I hate to say it, guys, but...
it's the miscellaneous box right now.
This one is specific.
We also need one arrow.
Maybe I should use these, actually.
Ah, but that doesn't work, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, too bad.
Oh, let me collect this.
Man, that's too bad, actually.
Maybe we should bring them anyway?
Just to use up first?
Because why not?
You know?
What else am I going to use them for?
Put that there.
So, when you go exploring, you definitely want some wood.
Let's take 15.
I want to put this in a box.
Like that.
Sticks we don't need.
I forgot to put the clipboard back here.
I'm going to do it right now.
This seems insane to walk all the way back over here and do it, but this is me being, you know, organized right now.
Otherwise, I will never get around to doing it.
Just get it done.
It's something you can apply in real life, too, you know?
There's a tiny thing that's been annoying you forever.
Maybe in your house, you know?
Maybe you needed to set up that picture.
And you just don't want to pull out the tools to do it and get it done.
But you just got to do it, man.
Just get it done.
And you don't have to think about it anymore.
Okay, I'm going to put this, if I can, here.
Oh, look at that, man!
Wonderful.
Surely I'll remember that it's there.
Okay.
I really should set up a little perimeter here.
This is what I mean.
I could have, you know, not done this now and said, nah, I'll do that later.
But no, I'm doing it now.
I'm getting it done.
Defending my homeland.
Oh, we also need proper food on this trip.
Please do not explode over there.
I will be so mad.
No problem.
Check your six.
Wait, we're almost 30.
We don't even need to go to the nether.
Just give me some more enemies.
Oh, you're a special one.
Water zombie.
You're a womby.
I like that name.
It's a good name.
Okay.
We're going to deposit this into the machine already.
Let me also put a little light in the center here.
There we go.
Off it goes.
Now, the miscellaneous toolbox.
We're going to fill this up with miscellaneous stuff.
Isn't that amazing?
I think it is.
Wait, are we even using these?
We are.
Okay, good.
Water pocket is good to have.
Let's go kill some monsters.
Oh, yeah.
That's my tunnel.
Now, where are the monsters?
Shouldn't there be a bunch here?
There's a cow.
Oh, actually, yes.
You need the steaks.
We also have a bunch of cows at home.
Let's not forget that.
We should probably feed them.
It's been a while.
Hit him.
There we go.
Thanks.
Wait, he has an enchanted bow.
Mind if I take that?
Oh, you bastard!
I thought I was out of range.
Can't believe it.
I'm 30, by the way.
Hooray!
Let's see if I can get a nice enchant on my bow.
Ah, wait a second!
I can't enchant the bow when it's already enchanted.
But I can enchant another bow, and then I can combine them.
That's what I can do.
It's fine.
Yeah.
Now, an item sorter, I think it's going to be super easy to make.
Now, obviously, I have to remember exactly how I did it in the last world I had.
But obviously, since we have filters and stuff here, this should be way easier.
And I'm not going to jump in with both feet until I have a solid understanding of all the different components of create.
You know?
So I don't miss out on any awesome ways to do it, basically.
Let's eat these.
Okay.
What was I doing just now?
What?
Why?
Oh, yeah.
Enchanting.
Good.
So we need a new bow.
Which means we need string.
Let's see if I remember this.
Three string.
We need a stick.
Actually, we had sticks in here, I think.
Yeah.
Oh, dude.
Why do we have all these sticks in here?
And an arrow, too.
Anything else I should...
Oh, torches?
Wait.
Yes.
These torches need to go...
in here.
Yep.
Okay.
So the bow needs...
And I think it's some wood as well.
Something like this.
Let's see if I'm right.
Hell yeah!
Oh, we didn't even need wood.
Okay.
Good enough.
Alright.
Wish me luck.
Oh, man!
But if I do this, there is a chance that it will give me what I want.
You know?
I am actually gonna gamble.
Do you believe?
Do you believe I can do it?
Watch this.
Oh, crap!
Man gambles and finds out.
More at nine.
Also, do I have any beef at all?
I actually have a little bit?
We should go feed these animals.
Let's do that.
Oh, we actually have a lot of cows here?
We definitely need to automate the slaughter of these cows.
Oh, wait.
Maybe I should feed them first before I kill them.
Reproduce!
Replicate!
Multiply!
Divide!
Okay, you want some of this, I guess?
Oh, wait.
I forgot to feed the sheep.
Okay.
You're all fed now.
Now the chickens.
Have sex.
Go.
Any more chickens?
Okay.
Let's kill the cows.
Ah.
Yo.
Maybe the plan is actually...
Uh...
Oh, wait.
I just discovered the ultimate way to gather meat from these animals.
This is the method, okay?
How do I get in?
So, basically, you feed them all, make sure they all have kids.
And then you kill all the adults.
Every time.
Then you come back and do the same thing later.
Now we only have kids.
Great!
And look at all that meat.
The problem is, if I keep doing this...
I'm actually halving the population every time.
Oh.
Okay.
So maybe we do this every third time.
Yeah.
Every third time we do this.
Ha ha ha ha.
Slight math...
Uh...
Issues there.
Well, that's fine.
Let me go smoke some stuff here.
I'm just gonna use wood.
Sue me.
I'm gonna use the wood I hate.
I hate this wood.
Smoke that beef.
I could go out and, uh...
Do it out here.
But I'm too lazy.
Okay?
It is by design.
Eggs are...
Food.
Last I heard.
Leather is definitely so miss, isn't it?
Also running out of wheat, which means we gotta go harvest that.
Lovely.
Maybe I want more wheat instead of potatoes.
Because the potatoes, you know...
They don't really give me much HP.
Or hunger.
Food.
You know what I mean.
A poisonous potato!
I wonder if there's a way to use that in Create.
For something.
I'm gonna burn the shield.
Ooh, we have to repair this.
Ran out of fuel.
Dude, let's burn the slabs.
Fuck these things.
That is actually such a good way to get rid of items you don't want like this, you know?
For example, these three oak slabs are just taking up a slot, ruining my whole day.
But we can burn them and get some use out of it.
That's not bad.
Ah, wait a minute.
Potatoes like that or...
Farming?
There's like an overlap here, isn't there?
Okay, you can cook the mutton too.
Ah, wait.
This is wrong.
I have a diamond pickaxe here.
What the hell?
Maybe...
You know what, actually?
Look!
Eighth...
Seventh slot.
Maybe I will...
Use the...
Wrench on the first slot.
This is now the first slot.
It's going there.
Also, we need to find diamonds, because I have none.
And my axe is soon done.
Which is not good for combat...
Reasons.
Yeah.
Dirt.
Definitely bring that.
I think we're ready.
Right?
So we go dig.
We do that.
We...
Yeah.
And...
Maybe I bring this now.
Because I did the enchanting already.
We don't have to think about that anymore.
I'm going to bring only one stack of this.
Then, of course, we also need...
This thing.
A cart assembler.
And we need one lever.
But the normal lever.
I don't have it.
Lever.
Easy.
There we go.
And that's it, right?
So we plop down the rails.
Put this on.
And plop down the minecart contraption.
Oh, maybe the glue we should bring.
Hand crank.
We don't need that yet.
And that's pretty much it, I think.
Perhaps bring some shitty blocks with us.
So we can use them as...
Roads.
Yeah.
Maybe not four stacks.
Let's just start with.
Because we're going to get more as we go along, right?
One stack.
Good.
Lovely.
We're ready.
Let's go dig.
Now the question is, how do I want to tame the world?
I'm taming the world in this direction.
Obviously, I want to tame it in different directions, too.
But let's start with this one over here.
We haven't even finished this direction here.
And it's actually quite close to the factory, which is great.
This is not great.
We'll fix that later.
A little bit of light.
It's always good to have some coal, especially if we want to make more torches.
We have efficiency three.
That's good.
That's the one that gives us more items when we mine.
So this is where we were at.
Until I stopped.
I don't know why I stopped here, actually.
Why did I stop here?
Keeping it neat.
Okay.
Let's see how fast I can do this.
One, two, three.
There.
Can I even put this on top?
No, let's not do that.
Lock.
Like that.
Yeah, this is correct.
It looked a little weird because it's the same block, but this is correct.
Do that.
And I think we're ready.
Five.
See how I'm changing my...
Wait, is it...
Maybe it's already glued.
How come I can't see the preview of it?
Oh, hold on.
Before we start.
Oh, it needs to...
Hold on.
Wait, it already has?
Or...
Oh, okay.
Well...
I am...
I'm honestly not sure what is happening.
Or why this is working right now.
It doesn't look like it has anything in its hand.
Maybe that's a bug.
Is it making a bridge?
Shit!
Stop!
Uh-oh.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's doing that thing again.
Oh, that's weird.
I knew something was wrong with it.
But it's fine.
I think it would be easier if we dig a little higher up.
But, you know, I don't have the opportunity to do that right now.
Let me try this again.
So, we put this...
Here.
Let me actually turn this off.
And then do it.
There we go.
Now it's locked like this.
Now I can look at it.
Now I can see the glue.
Great.
Let's have a look up top.
There should be chests up here.
Unless I took those down.
Nope.
They are there.
This is the funky thing.
You know, they are inside of the wall.
Maybe it's better if I put those on here instead.
Yeah, let's actually make this neat.
We're going to be using this machine for a while.
Grab everything.
But then we have to re-glue it.
Let's not forget that.
Okay.
It's going to be a little messy.
So we can actually...
Let's just disengage the glue on those.
And fill this up again.
Like that.
This one is not glued.
No, it's not.
So we can remove that.
These are not needed either.
The question is, where do we put these chests now?
Yo!
Check it out.
This is actually great.
We're going to put it...
I was about to say on either side, but then I can't pass later.
That's not good.
Why not down here, actually?
Ah, but then we can't open it right.
That's no good.
But on the bottom we can.
I could just put...
One chest.
Or three.
Like that.
Hey, that works!
Do we even need this right here?
Yeah, I think we do.
It should all be one now?
I think that works.
I think we got it.
Lock rotation.
Here we go.
And hold on before we go.
How many do you have?
Okay, good.
Now, the one in front...
There's one in front that's placing blocks.
That was the whole issue right now, actually.
Let's fix that.
I almost forgot.
Oh, wait.
Maybe I never did that?
On this machine.
Oh, hold on a second.
Oh, crap.
I need another deployer.
Yeah.
I was like, why isn't it making a bridge?
And the reason is...
It can't.
Because I never made it make that.
Or designed it that way.
Or we're going to design it now.
So we need one deployer.
We need a bunch of...
I wonder if I can make it so that the deployer automatically grabs...
Yo, maybe like...
A Tom Holland.
We bring in Tom Holland to do the dirty work.
Like, he may seem like an innocent guy, but trust me.
He dirty.
We have one here.
I was thinking...
What does it take to make one?
Ah, crap.
I don't have any iron.
I'm actually going to steal this.
We don't need it right now.
Yeah.
This will be good.
And we're just going to run with two chests.
Who cares?
It's fine.
We don't need anything else, I don't think.
That's good.
Oh my god.
Isn't this beautiful, guys?
Look at this.
Water comes down from the mountain.
Turns this big water wheel.
Turns these gears.
Goes inside the ground.
Turns a rod.
That then turns this wheel.
Which turns this turbine.
Or not a turbine.
It's like a...
I don't even know what the word is for that.
But it sucks up water, right?
Brings it into this container.
Where we have heat underneath.
Which boils this water.
Turns it into steam.
That drives this wheel.
That then drives the factory.
So damn cool.
Love it.
And cheers to that.
Also.
There's bees right here.
They're not ready for me, though.
I wonder why.
Is it because I need to put the fire underneath them first?
But that doesn't sound right either, does it?
Something's going on.
With that bee house.
Also, I think I'm gonna rearrange these chests.
They're gonna be placed a little differently.
And you get a full stack.
Ah, but wait, wait.
Let me try this.
There.
We fill this up.
With a bunch of stone.
And you know what?
We can probably do the same thing with...
With this one, right?
Oh.
No, I didn't mean to push.
Back, back, back, back, back, back, back.
Unless we're ready.
No, we're not ready.
We're not ready.
Back, back you go.
Oh, I can just do this now.
There we go.
Let's not push it.
Where did the...
I hear a zombie.
Oh, this is a mess now.
Wait, why can't I...
Oh, right.
There we go.
Here, we need to glue this first, of course.
Now it's connected.
Oh.
This one needs to be there as well.
And then, of course, the chests.
Let's not forget those.
Oh, it's almost too perfect.
We put them here.
Look.
And then I can walk through it as well.
That's beautiful.
The design is improving.
Oh, that is...
That is wonderful.
Have to give me that.
Okay.
This one is filled up.
Give it some more.
Alrighty.
Are we ready?
Oh.
Lock rotation.
And...
Go!
Whoa, I just had a lag spike.
I'm taking this with me already.
That thing's gonna start digging now.
And the great thing is, when it's exposing some iron or anything I need, then I come and grab it.
And we should soon be out on the other side of this mountain.
Maybe I should also have some way to stop it real fast, in case we have problems.
You know, I'm gonna be up front here, ready to run in front and move it the other way, you know?
God, I love this so much.
The ultimate miner.
A green cave.
Why did it stop?
Did you run out of...
Oh, I see.
Wait, did I give it to you or not?
I did.
Okay.
This one definitely has more.
I can't open the...
Oh, shit.
I can't open the hopper while it's moving.
Let me push it a bit more.
Look at this here.
A little side cave.
Getting some experience on top of it all.
Actually, I need this diorite.
What the hell is that?
Oh, it's tough.
I thought it was a new block.
Wait, this is new.
No, it's not.
Well, it is new, but it's not new-new.
You know what I mean?
We actually kind of need copper, too.
So it's kind of essential that I grab this.
I think you ran out of these ones, maybe?
Faster.
Dude, when are we out on the other side of this mountain?
Come on.
Dig.
Yeah, iron.
That's what I really need.
Aesthetics are important, guys.
I'm going to keep going until we're on the other side of this mountain.
So my question now is, let's say the hopper is running low.
So we can't make bridges anymore.
What is the easiest way to stop this thing so I can refill it?
I think I have to use the wrench.
Right-click it, plop down some tracks, and then push it into the cart assembler real quick.
Oh god, what's happening?
That was a weird sound.
Oh, I need this diorite, actually.
I can't just...
Okay, let's say the time is now.
Yeah, let's stop it now.
Oh!
Fucking hell.
Put down another?
Come on, one more.
And there we go!
That's how you do it!
Don't even need the wrench.
Now we open this.
Oh, there's plenty!
There's plenty!
All right, well...
Yeah.
I'm happy.
This is one big tunnel.
I don't think I've ever made a tunnel that is this big in Minecraft ever.
Maybe I have.
I've done some SLJs in my time, okay?
Oh, and I can't open these chests because there's rock above, so I need to do that.
Look at all of this!
It even took some copper on its way!
Incredible!
I'm gonna fill...
Yo!
Wait, it's not...
There we go.
I'm gonna fill this up.
Look at the...
mechanics here.
Wait, I'm just...
doing that.
I'm gonna fill this up, uh...
as we go.
There you go.
Coal as well.
Iron.
I will eat these glowberries.
When I can.
I can't eat them yet.
But I will.
So the easiest way to just start again now is to just do this.
And then we keep going!
Oh, wait.
I need to push it first.
Okay.
There we go.
And we...
We continue on!
I feel like I have reached a new level of enlightenment here.
And look at this here.
Goodies are being revealed.
I love me some goodies.
Uh, this is clay.
And this tunnel will be a tunnel for trains.
The thing is, though, I don't even know how trains are gonna work.
Like, how big are they gonna be?
You know?
Oh, faster.
Come on.
We gotta go faster than this.
Yo, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Maybe I can put this...
So obviously we need a steam engine for a train.
At least that's what I imagine.
So if we put this in front of a train...
It'll be able to drive on its own.
Maybe that's the endgame goal here for the train situation.
This is so incredible.
When are we out on the other side?
Hello?
I can't believe this.
We've been going for ages.
Here.
Get refilled.
Okay, guys.
When we reach the other side and we come out the mountain...
Is it gonna be day or night?
Horizontal day or night, Gamble.
The ultimate question.
We've never had one of these.
I think it's gonna be night.
Oh!
I'm so good!
Yeah, we made it out!
Fantastic!
Wait, uh...
Maybe we should stop now.
Do I keep digging?
I like the idea of just digging still.
Because we should... Yeah, look at this!
Oh, that reminds me.
I forgot my bed.
That's one thing I forgot from home.
Oh, it's time to stop this thing.
We officially made it out and it's too perfect.
Look!
We're gonna make a bridge across here!
Oh my god.
It's gonna be insane.
Oh, yeah.
Light it up.
Man, that is one long tunnel.
Damn.
Let's take this with us.
Oh.
Wait.
What the fuck?
That's weird.
Why did that happen?
That doesn't even make any sense.
The fuck?
Okay.
We have to put this back on.
I thought I was gonna die.
Okay.
We gotta stop this.
Stop this.
Stop.
No.
No!
I got it.
It got a little bit messy at the end there.
But otherwise, I would say clean, slick operation here.
I run a clean ledger.
That's a crime right there.
Now we bring it back home.
We have lots of goodies.
Oh, one thing I need to go grab is... I need to grab a bed.
And the other thing that is essential, a boat.
And then I have to go into the mines, like, deep down and find some diamond.
Because this axe is about to be destroyed.
And we also gotta just refresh some diamond tools, you know?
And while we're down there, we're gonna kill some mobs to get experience.
And then we're gonna try, yet again, to see if we can get a nice bow.
That's the plan.
Oh, yeah.
Wait, I'm already outside?
Ah!
This tunnel's not as long as I thought it was.
I mean, it's long, but not that long.
Oh, it's a sheep.
Let's get the shovel.
I didn't use eight, I used nine.
What was that?
Oh, it's the steam thingy.
Okay.
Let's fill this guy up.
And, yeah.
Oh, wait, I have a bunch of diorite now, so let's just do that now.
I wonder, can I just put this...
No, I can't, okay.
Let me do this the minimal way.
Just like that.
Okay, what do we got here?
Ooh, not that much diorite.
What the hell?
I only got 24 diorite through that whole tunnel.
Blows my damn mind.
Oh, we're gonna be blasting like crazy.
The ultimate blast.
Unfortunately, not a lot of iron or zinc.
This is very bad.
Trees and sticks, huh?
I'm gonna deposit some more wood into this thing.
Yep.
This one we can fill up with a bit of cobblestone, since we have it.
And you know what?
I may actually cook the last bit of cobblestone there.
Let's put the diorite in here.
No, this one.
Oh, it still has a lot?
I guess it's backed up here.
That's the problem right now.
The problem we have right now is that this thing needs nuggets.
More specifically, the hopper on this one.
I guess we'll take it back.
I used five.
Uh, how did it go?
Let me see.
I think it's simply...
this... one.
Like that.
Oh, I have to cook them first before I can...
turn them into nuggets.
This is gonna be the ultimate blasting session.
We're gonna blast everything all at once.
What do I not need?
I kinda need everything.
Gotta get rid of this water.
Let me grab the lava.
Time to blast.
Get ready for this.
We're gonna blast all of this stone as well.
Damn, that's a lot.
The efficiency here is off the charts.
Imagine how much coal we save right now by doing this.
If we did this the old way, that's easily like half a stack or even like a full stack of coal, I think.
Actually, I have no idea.
It could also be three stacks.
Could be one quarter of one stack.
I don't know.
And there it is.
They're all... yeah, they're all cooked.
Oh!
Did you hear that?
Man!
That was like 50 sounds stacked on top of each other.
Almost perfectly.
Holy crap!
That's a lot.
We even made some ingots.
This is for the hopper.
So these iron ingots we needed to make a saw.
This was the next step.
Stone two.
All this coal, let's just distribute this.
Because at some point I do want to just keep it simple and smoke things and, you know, cook things here.
When I'm lazy, it happens.
These chests are...
Why do I have two chests?
Okay, whatever.
I want a couple more of these.
Let me also...
I think I should be wearing the goggles more.
You know, because they are kind of useful.
Some other blocks reveal information such as item and fluid content.
Yeah.
I definitely want to keep these, I think.
At least have them in this box, you know?
No, actually the wood stays in here.
For exploration purposes.
Lava needs to go back.
Rotten flesh is in here.
Oh, yes.
And you know what?
Let's go smash some of this copper.
Oh, I also need to smash a little bit of iron first, actually.
One, two, three.
Let's smash three of them.
Oh, one of them did not...
take.
Why is it not doing that?
I don't want to right click, but then it smashes everything.
Okay, whatever.
I think we needed three...
Three.
I'm gonna keep the remaining.
But I will smash a whole stack of this.
Now.
Um...
Saw.
Casing.
There it is.
Now we take the crank.
Now we're ready to grab wood as well.
Isn't it just lovely?
Now the question is, should I bring my...
digging machine for this?
Hmm.
I don't think so.
I think everything related to the digging machine needs to go in here.
Let me go pick that up.
And actually, maybe also cook the remaining...
cobblestone that I have there.
Right now the limiting factor is...
diorite, actually.
Lovely.
So the way to do this is to power this first.
Ah, I forgot the lever.
Hmm.
Look at my house.
Dude, I get crazy nostalgic listening to these songs now.
And I know it's nothing compared to you guys, you know, but...
It's been a couple years since I started this game at first.
But even then, you know, now...
I'm feeling the nostalgia.
It's weird.
Oh, let's go cook this.
So all of this needs to be turned into...
little stones at some point.
Let me grab the lava.
Hey, you know what, actually?
Since I'm doing this...
Let's just...
put the potatoes in too.
Since we're at it, right?
Ah, wait, wait!
Blasting potatoes is probably gonna...
overcook it.
That's not a good idea, actually.
I changed my mind.
Whoops!
I almost made a big mistake.
Isn't it nice just listening to this?
Knowing that...
stuff is being worked on...
while you do other things.
I think it's like...
20 seconds...
that it takes.
I think I should put my bucket inside of here too.
Because I do use it often, but not that often, you know?
Maybe the left side is for tools, the right side is for...
resources that is needed on...
on the go.
clay balls?
I would say that is...
miscellaneous.
Yep.
Potatoes are...
Let's just...
be lazy here.
There you go.
Smoke those bastards.
And let's grab the...
lever real quick.
So we can pick up the machine.
And this should be just as easy as doing this...
and that!
It doesn't even feel that silly right now.
But it's definitely silly.
Leave nothing behind.
Good.
This needs to be spruced up with some...
plants and some bushes, you know?
Some beautiful plants...
and flowers...
stuff like that.
Oh, we have some extra.
Yo, you know what I should have?
I should have a toolbox just for this.
You know, the toolbox...
called the digging machine or something.
And you know what?
I can actually rename them.
Let's not forget that's a thing.
Um...
Yeah, this axe needs to be replaced.
We gotta go find a new one right now.
There's a cooking...
Now, is there something I forgot?
Yes.
A bed and a...
boat.
Where is...
Oh, I think I put my bed in the...
Yeah, it's next to the factory.
I just make a new one.
I think we need three of these.
Just make it.
I'm gonna color it.
If I can.
Maybe an ink sack, right?
That makes color.
Yeah!
Oh, look at that!
A bunch of new things.
Anythings...
Okay, that was definitely a black handlebar.
Speaking of, you know what?
We should bring a...
Let's bring some rope!
Ultimate exploration device.
Wait, how did I...
Wait, maybe that doesn't work like that?
Wait, what?
What?
How did I just see this?
Rope!
Now it's gone.
Huh?
I'm confused.
Why can't I see this?
Oh, is it...
Oh, right, okay.
It's the crafting bench.
We need some of this.
And some string.
Let's experiment with this.
Wait, I actually think I have this already.
Yeah, I have some here.
Let me see.
Oh, wait, maybe I can't...
Let me ponder that.
Right, okay.
Rope winch and connector.
I see.
I guess this is the winch and this is the connector.
Ah, man.
I was hoping I could just, you know, sling over a rope over a cliffside and then, you know, go down it or something.
But maybe I can with this.
I just don't know how to make it yet.
Right-click holding a wrench to...
Yeah, look, that sounds so cool, doesn't it?
I want to do this.
I like that they're using a little, um...
Uh...
Paraguay or whatever.
You know, the singing bird.
For the illustrations.
I'm going to put the black dye on my bed.
You can't stop me.
We're making a black bed.
Now, smelting.
Go in.
Strings.
Same with you.
Go in here.
I think I'm ready.
Rope cobbling is officially dead.
It don't work that way.
Let's go.
Quick sleeping session.
I'll be right back.
By the way, let me set the stage for you.
Um...
Jackie...
Usually she jumps on my table, right?
So I think I fixed the problem now.
I bought her another bed.
Like a little cat bed on a barrel, you know?
Like one of those cat tree thingies, but it's like a barrel with a bed on top.
And I put it in this room as well.
So now she has two of them.
And she's lying right next to me now, in a little cat bed.
And she's so comfortable.
Isn't that nice?
And maybe it'll prevent her from jumping up.
We'll see if that happens today or not, but...
Usually it happens towards the end of the stream when it's feeding time, you know?
So we'll see how that goes.
And she's very happy about it so far.
She's very, very blessed.
At least I try to do as much as I can for her, you know?
She's my baby.
I love her.
Okay.
Let's go explore.
Now, I could just follow my own torches here.
And I think I may actually do that.
Let's just keep going.
There's definitely places I haven't been down here yet.
Look at this!
Great start.
So the goal is diamonds.
Oh, hold on!
We may need to construct a compass at some point.
To not get lost, right?
It is a real problem.
For me.
But I mean, as long as we have torches here, I shouldn't be lost.
Let me kill you before I go down.
Oh god, here we go.
My axe is about to break.
I'm keeping an eye on it.
Man, I love these spectral arrows.
They're the best.
Ooh!
Oh!
Enderman.
Oi!
Hey!
Very nice.
Look at all these!
They have grown!
Not even sure what I can use these on yet.
Other than, you know, spyglass.
Oh, I guess I can make black glass.
Or tinted glass.
That's one use case.
Cool.
I'm just gonna jump.
Yeah!
Light up the area.
I also brought wood in case I need to make a new axe down here when I find diamonds.
Everything is accounted for.
Oh, gold is actually the one element that I'm lacking quite of.
I don't have a lot of it.
And I do find myself needing it.
Here and there.
Very nice.
Wait, what is that?!
Aserene!
I'm not sure what the point is of these weird blocks.
Like, what am I gonna use those for?
I guess you can use them aesthetically.
But like, functionally?
Seems useless.
So I've been here before.
Oh man, I need to start making, um...
What do you call it?
Night vision potions.
We need carrots for that one.
How come I didn't pick any of this up when I was here?
I guess I was just focused on diamonds or something.
This we also need a lot of.
Oh, hello there.
Follow me.
Dude, is this like the gold biome or something?
Why is there so much of it?
They're being super stinchy with diamonds.
Let's go this way.
Dude, I need to tell you about this, because it's been bugging me the last couple days.
So, I have a dishwasher, right?
Yay, dishwashers.
And, unfortunately, this dishwasher is making the most annoying, high-pitched, you know, ultra-frequent sound.
You know like those old TVs?
That would make that high-pitched sound?
That old people couldn't hear?
That's the sound it makes, but like, amplified times 10 when it's running.
And it's driving me crazy.
So, this guy came over, and he wanted to repair it.
And, of course, he's old.
He was like, I don't hear anything.
There's nothing wrong with it.
And I go, there is something wrong with it.
You just can't hear it, because you're old.
And I did say that.
I was like, how old are you?
He's like, 57.
I said, you're old, you can't hear it.
And he almost didn't believe me.
It was at the point where he thought that this was wasting his time.
Trying to fix this dishwasher, you know?
Because why did I drive here 30 minutes?
I can't hear anything.
There's nothing wrong with this thing.
So, I had to argue with him for quite a while.
And that really pissed me off.
So, now he's apparently, you know, reporting back to HQ.
For someone else to come over.
And it's like, dude.
Just trust me, like...
He even turned it off and was like, now it's gone.
And he did some settings on it, you know?
And I'm like, now I hear it, now I don't.
And he really thought I was taking the piss, you know?
Anyway, I just had to tell you that because it bothered me so much.
Very annoying.
Like, why would I be calling him out here?
Just to waste his time, you know?
It's not like I'm doing this just to be an asshole or something.
It's weird.
Oh, yeah.
And I think... I don't know about cats, but maybe cats can hear that...
High-frequency sound as well.
I was trying to see if Jackie could hear it.
I'm not quite sure.
But, if it's like really annoying to her, then it's also really a big problem, right?
Because whenever I run the dishwasher, it would be terrible for her.
Dude, is it me or is there like a lot of fucking iron here?
Is this a giga deposit?
And there's tough as well!
Dude, this may actually be a giga deposit.
Let me, uh, see.
Let's see.
If it keeps appearing, then we know...
Oh, yeah.
Oh, dude.
I think this is it.
Kinda wish I had the digging machine now.
Actually, no, I don't.
Because it's actually kind of a bother.
To set up, you know?
And then it only mines in one direction, then it's...
Yeah, yada, yada, yada.
Not amazing.
We're gonna have so many nuggets when we come home!
We're gonna have floor for weeks.
Also, I got four diamonds.
I was...
I was so focused on telling that story just now that I forgot I got it.
So, I think it's time we make another axe before it breaks.
Let's do it.
So, hold on.
Um...
Now it's like at zero, right?
Let me read this.
Every inventor's dearest companion conveniently holds a large amount of eight different item types.
Okay.
When picked up, retains inventory contents.
When placed in range, nearby players can hold the toolbox...
The toolbox keybind to access its contents remotely.
When right-clicked, open...
Okay, but, uh...
What do you mean by...
Holding the...
Wait, there was...
There was a keybind for this.
I forgot about this.
Hold on.
Keybinds...
Uh, what was it called?
Uh...
Toolbox.
Let's see.
Create.
Wait a minute.
Open block ro...
Oh!
Wait, block rotation menu?
I gotta bind that!
Uh...
Button five on the mouse, maybe?
Maybe button four?
The hell is that?
Focus...
Uh...
Okay, so it's left alt.
Got it.
Wait, physics staff.
Oh, create simulator?
Ponder?
Maybe it would make sense to put this on something other than W, because it's walk forward.
Nah, but it's fine.
It's working fine now.
Okay!
Oh, that's right!
I almost forgot about this!
Oh, man, that's...
Yo, hold on a minute.
When you're building things...
Like, let's say I was making the factory.
I have this toolbox nearby, with common items that I need while building.
I just go like this, right?
Do whatever I need to do.
Boom.
But the problem is, I need to get used to this workflow, you know?
I'm not used to it, so right now, it's more of a bother than a help.
So, when I get used to it, it's gonna be immensely powerful, I think.
I just need to get to that point, right?
And right now, when I click left alt, nothing happens, because it's not placed.
So I can even do this.
What if I have two... oh, wait, hold on.
Oh!
Okay, so I get...
So, one, two, three, four, five, six.
One, two, three, four, five...
One, two, three, four, five, six...
Okay.
Hmm.
Maybe they keep adding on to it then.
Anyway, let's fill this up.
Like that.
Maybe some cobblestone as well.
Good.
Very nice.
Let's keep looking for iron.
Oh, I was gonna make a new axe, that's right.
Let's do that now.
That's why I did this, and then I got distracted by the toolbox stuff.
That's why I took this.
Right.
Oh, gotta make some of these.
Four is enough.
And we need the diamonds.
Good.
Now, honestly, I could also just make a...
Like an iron axe.
I think they're kind of close in damage.
It's like fine, you know.
Wait, let me do this.
There you go.
And...
Oh, let me put this one back as well.
This is like a tool.
You can probably have...
No, you can't do that.
Okay.
Let's put these in here too.
Free up some space.
And the boat as well.
It's not often that you...
Oh, look at this helmet!
Protection three, unbreaking three.
That's quite a nice helmet.
The rest is good.
I'm gonna get rid of this.
No, I'm not.
I will use it until it breaks.
I'm so glad I have efficiency on my pickaxe right now.
Yeah, follow the tough.
Ooh!
Oh.
Okay.
Ooh!
Wait a minute!
Yo!
We should try and get Skulk and all that stuff!
No doubt that will unlock some new shit and create.
Not to mention stuff like, uh...
End blocks, you know?
Stuff from the end.
We need to go to both places.
I wonder if there's anything, like, really nice to get there, you know?
Progression-wise, it would make sense.
Okay, so I'm running a little dry on iron there.
So maybe it's this way?
No.
Let's go back to the beginning here.
Look at all this tough.
Oh.
Christ.
Yeah.
It's concentrated around this part.
Oh!
Look at that one!
A big boy!
Where are you?
Oh!
Oh, you asshole.
Gotcha.
Oh, that was just the arrow falling down.
Man, this is an insane mining expedition.
One of the most fruitful ones I've had in a while.
The only thing I would like a little bit more of is diamonds.
Nothing more in this direction.
My pickaxe is also gonna break soon.
And I really don't want that to break.
Hold on, I'm not getting that much iron!
Wait.
Fuck.
Guys.
I don't think efficiency is the one that gives me more items.
It's fortune.
Or whatever it's called.
Oh, no.
Oh, well.
I mean, nothing I can do about it now.
I really thought I was collecting, like, big bucks right now, you know?
And I'm not.
It's not even that much iron.
But, you know, let's not look a gift horse in the mouth.
We were gifted this awesome place.
Let's just suck it dry as much as we can.
While we're here.
And take the win.
Okay, looks like we're about there.
Oh.
Most of it.
Let's move on.
Let's find those diamonds.
There's some.
I think I saw more.
No.
One measly diamond.
I don't wanna go that way.
I'm a little scared of going up to the surface again.
Me thinks I'm gonna be very lost.
Please kill each other.
Hey, we got more, uh, amethysts.
And zinc.
zinc has been kinda rare.
In these parts.
And normally it's everywhere.
I'm not even gonna go in there.
I don't need more.
This pickaxe is about to break.
Also, we're level 30.
Maybe the next thing we enchant is a pickaxe.
Imagine we get fortune on it.
Or looting.
I think it's fortune.
Looting is the one on the sword.
I always get those two mixed up for some reason.
Yeah, when my pickaxe breaks- No, I'm not gonna break it actually.
We're gonna leave it.
Hey, we have fortune one on it though!
I didn't even see that!
Hey, we have fortune on it already!
Well, it's not the good fortune.
It's the shitty one.
But hey.
It's fine.
Wait, is this another giga deposit?
You gotta be shitting me.
No way.
No!
Not now!
When my pickaxe is about to break.
Also ran out of coal here.
Oops, wrong one.
Yeah, when those run out, we're out of here.
I don't care.
You know what, actually?
I probably need my pickaxe to get out of here too, so...
Here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna dig up right here, because we're gonna be able to come back to this spot later.
We're going straight up.
No, that's smart.
I'm gonna podcast for a little while.
Day or night.
I say dusk!
Didn't see that one coming, did you?
I'm actually not sure if dusk is before the sun comes up, or right after the sun comes up.
Or...
If it's like right after the sun comes up, or if it's right before the sun goes down.
There's also twilight.
Oh, twilight has to be, like, before the sun goes down.
Right before the sun goes down.
Maybe it's opposite.
It's gonna be night!
Oh, my pickaxe!
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Uh...
Guys?
Will I get out?
Before the pickaxe breaks?
I say yes.
Oh my god.
Don't do this to me!
Oh my god, how far down are we?
Ah!
Oh no!
Wait, how do we get out?
Oh wait, I didn't think about this.
I... oh shit.
We have to, we have to make a new pickaxe.
Fuck!
I made a big mistake.
Oh no.
Um...
It's fine.
Oven.
Coal.
Cook.
Easy.
Wait, we have...
Wait, what was the...
Wait, wait, wait.
Hold on, do we have any wood?
Oh, thank god!
Oh my god, that was a close one.
That was a close one.
Damn.
Okay, we're fine.
We're cooking.
Literally.
Otherwise it would have been a pain to get out of here.
We would have had to punch our way out.
Maybe I should have just made a stone pickaxe.
You know what actually?
Yes.
We're making a stone one.
I can't get rid of the oven!
Wait, uh...
Fill this up, man.
With everything I have.
Dude, I'm actually kinda...
I'm panicking a little bit.
It's like I'm paralyzed.
One, two, three.
Right, so now we need, now we need this...
Here we go.
It's fine.
Easy, we...
There we go.
Man, I was just in a state of paralysis just now.
That was weird.
I still say NIGHT!
It's night.
You'll see.
Imagine if it was one block further up and it was outside.
Right below your feet, huh?
Up, up, up!
Go, go, go, go!
Okay, I was way further down than I thought I was.
Yeah, there's no way I would have made that at all.
Not even close.
I don't wanna use andesite.
Andesite is suddenly one of the most valuable commodities in Minecraft.
Get ready to see the moon.
Here we go.
Off!
Dude, I have never had, like, a gaming session where I was correct every time.
It is actually impossible!
Well, let's say I dig up seven times in a stream.
So it's like a half, you know.
Times a half.
The chances are getting pretty low, okay?
Also, I'm not lost at all.
I'm right here.
It's beautiful.
Um...
Yeah, no problem.
I wonder if, uh, leaves actually soften the blow a little bit.
Oh wait, my axe!
I almost broke my axe!
Ooh, it's close to being destroyed.
Look at that!
Wait.
It's a shitty axe anyway!
Destroy it, man!
Who cares?
Yeah.
For some reason I thought it was enchanted, but it's not.
Okay, I'm level 31.
I am going to check my pickaxe, and I'm gonna check a bow.
And we'll see.
I have a pickaxe ready.
Somewhere.
This needs to be turned into normal-ass iron.
Uh, we should totally blast this.
Soon.
Only one measly diamond.
Is what I got out of that.
Wait, how did I disenchant?
Display board?
I forgot how to disenchant.
Uh...
Uh, I know.
I know, I know.
It's the, um...
Gah!
Uh, smithing- smithing table!
Iron oak.
Two.
Let's put that outside.
Fuck!
Wait, it...
I forgot which one it was, man.
Ah, hold on.
It's somewhere, it's somewhere in here.
Oh, that's so annoying.
Wait, even better.
Uh...
Ah, shit, no.
It's, it's like the smithing table, but the other one, you know what I mean?
Dude, I can't believe...
Like, how is it not the smithing table?
It's not the cauldron.
I'm trying to remember my last house, the one in season two.
Where would I go to disenchant every time?
I went to...
Uh, it was right in front of my house.
And it was...
It was, yeah.
It was...
It was right in front of the door.
Wait!
No.
I was about to say disenchanting table, but that's another thing I don't think.
Ha ha ha ha!
Uh...
Why am I blanking on this right now?
It doesn't exist.
I have not discovered it.
It is not in the game right now.
This bow is about to...
Wait, that's power one.
I will save the items that need to be disenchanted for later.
This needs to go to hell.
Oh, it doesn't want to...
Die.
There we go.
New pickaxes!
Oh, we can't even make a new one!
Don't even have the...
Dude, I went out there to get diamonds!
And I don't even have it!
That's crazy.
Wow.
I feel scammed.
Like the ultimate scam here.
This one needs to be disenchanted too.
Diamonds.
Oh, wait, I've...
No, I need three.
Wait...
Yes, I have an extra!
Mmm...
I don't like...
Okay.
Let me...
Let me see the bow.
Show me the bow.
One, two, three.
And then, uh, three sticks.
Power me.
I'm sh...
Okay, we're gonna...
We're gonna gamble.
Wish me luck.
Second gamble of the day.
Here we go.
This will give me...
Fortune three.
Fuck!
Don't gamble, kids.
It's bad.
Ah!
Shit, man.
But you know what?
I can combine these.
Let's make a crazy pickaxe here.
Wait, this one has efficiency four.
That's kinda crazy.
Wait a sec.
Oh wait, I broke my other pickaxe.
I have massive regret!
I do.
There's a lot of it.
I regret it all.
I actually can't believe I've done this.
Well, we have a bow ready for enchanting if we need it later.
Burn us.
Maybe I should carry that around?
In my toolbox?
Nah.
Yes.
You know what?
Yes, actually.
Let's carry one of these around at all times.
And one of these too.
This is now the new standard.
See that?
It may seem like a waste because this is like, you can have a lot of items in there, but...
I think it's worth it.
Now we need some...
of that.
Yeah.
That's unfortunate.
I will just have to run with, I think, I guess this pickaxe here.
We don't want this one.
Yep.
This shovel has been going for a while.
Redstone.
Did I empty this?
I did.
Okay, well...
Good.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I can combine these two.
Make it better?
Costs eight?
I feel like that's not worth it.
I'm gonna save my levels, because I'm so close to 30 still.
Yeah, I'll keep my infinity.
Yeah, that's fine.
I think I want to put my bed in here too.
Ah, in it, no.
The bed is actually so used, that I want to have it ready at all times.
Okay.
Let's go find some...
Hmm...
Ah man, what do I need to do right now?
Oh, right.
We gotta turn these into nuggets, so we gotta blast them first.
Let's bring some stone as well.
I have so much of it.
Uh, we need a bucket.
Massive blasting session.
Cheers to that.
While that's happening...
We go to sleep.
And...
Now.
Ah.
Maybe it's like 30 seconds.
I think it's half a minute.
Also, we have to make a lot of alloys.
But that is being mated by the machine.
I wonder if I should make some kind of custom output where I can grab alloys on the wave I need to.
Instead of having the machine stop, uh, you know, when it can't produce anymore.
Maybe have like an in-between chest.
Where the alloys get stacked up.
And instead of having it being stacked on the belt.
That's actually better.
So that I can go grab certain things when I need them.
Okay.
Now with all this stone, we should make some...
bricks.
Nice.
I'm also gonna go blast these real quick.
Let's make a couple cracked ones.
Not too many.
Just a couple.
Three stacks.
And we have 28 zinc ingots.
Look at this.
It's gonna make so many- Oh my goodness.
Whoa!
Okay, dude.
We are gonna have floors in no time.
And let's start working on the train.
I need to figure out how to make a train.
This is the next big thing.
So this one's good.
Let's fill the...
hopper up with this.
Actually use these ones first.
Wow, we kinda need more than...
this.
Beautiful!
Oh yeah.
Oh, wood of course!
That's the one thing we're lacking right now.
Let me grab some of those.
I think I have two stacks of logs.
Exactly the right amount.
I'm gonna grab these.
This is done now.
Doesn't that just feel amazing?
Picking up all that.
Now we've filled this up with wood.
And we're gonna have so many...
uh...
And the side alloys.
No, casings.
That's what's coming out of this.
Good.
And I'm still carrying around the saw, right?
I am.
In case I need to do that.
Alright!
The machinery is back in action!
Look!
It's something to behold, isn't it?
I will say, though, there's a bit of a, uh...
What's the word for it?
When there's a problem.
Well, it's not a problem.
It's a bottleneck right here.
This thing is a little slow in producing these, compared to how fast these are coming.
I think.
Actually, no.
It's...
It's just in time.
J-I-T.
Almost...
It's a little slower.
Yeah, it's not just in time.
It's nearly just in time.
Okay, let's...
Let's start to look...
At potential trains.
Where would I look for this?
Movement anchors, perhaps?
Physics behavior.
Springs.
Sticker?
Ideal for redstone controlled block attachment.
Upon receiving a signal, it will toggle its state.
Okay.
You know what?
I wonder if this can be used to...
Remove the simulated aspect of my contraption with the digging machine faster, somehow.
Okay, let's just go craft some new things.
I think that's where I'm at right now, you know?
I do have a bunch of new blocks that I can make.
And I haven't really done it yet.
That's gonna fuel my...
Discovery queue, so to speak.
First of all, get rid of the shield, because it's blocking my vision and it's annoying.
Inventory is fine, let me just fix it a little bit.
Okay, let's see.
What do we got?
What is new?
In here.
Let's try this one, mechanical crafter.
So we need a brass casing, electron tube, and crafting table.
I have all of that.
There.
Electron tube.
Oh yeah.
And brass casing.
That's just with brass, I guess.
Uh...
Would it be...
Ingot?
Wait, I'm actually...
Hold on.
Really?
Yep.
Wonderful.
And now we should be able to make that.
Here we go!
New recipes unlocked.
Let's...
Let's have a look.
Whoa, what?
An array of mechanical crafters can be used to automate any crafting recipe.
I'mma stop you right there.
I'mma let you finish.
But...
What is the crafter for them?
Hello?
Is there already a block that does this?
Just saying.
Using a wrench, the crafter's paths can be arranged?
I don't even know what that means.
For a valid setup, all paths have to converge into one exit at any side.
Uh-huh.
Dude, what is even happening right now?
We're playing Snake.
The outputs will be placed into the inventory at the exit.
Oh, is that why I got three of them when I crafted it?
We're supposed to use these in bulk?
Mechanical crafters require rotational force to operate.
What the fuck?
What do you mean?
Right-click the front to insert items manually.
But why...
Okay, well...
Once every slot of a path contains an item, the crafting process will begin.
Okay, that's actually kind of cool, the way that was just animated.
For recipes not fully occupying the crafter setup, the start can be forced using a redstone pulse.
Right.
Or, in other words, a gym.
Oh, wait!
I see now!
This is like a crafting grid!
3x3!
Oh, shit!
I see how that works now.
But...
Okay, does it matter where the output is, though?
Could I not make it there?
Let's see.
Items can be inserted to crafters automatically?
Yeah, I figured.
So we'd have to have an input on each, or...
What?
Using the wrench at their backs, mechanical crafter inputs can be combined.
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
So the same item goes in both slots?
Is that it?
Same items in every slot?
What?
All connected crafters can now be accessed by the same input location.
Oh, wait, never mind.
No, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Yes!
Okay!
Amazing!
That's gonna make...
Uh...
A door!
Yeah!
I know my doors!
Oh!
More?
Some recipes will require additional crafters to bridge gaps in the path.
Wait, hold on.
Say that again?
Wait, slower, dude!
Slower!
Slow!
Some recipes will require additional crafters to bridge gaps in the path.
Oh!
Because they can't physically reach!
I guess.
Or what?
Using slot covers, crafters can be set to act as an empty slot in the arrangement.
Bucket!
This is...
Okay, hold on.
First...
What do you call it?
Instinct or...
Impression here?
Why go through all this trouble when you have the crafter?
Am I crazy?
Like, this seems...
But then again, I don't know if the crafter is as...
The thing is, I haven't ever used the crafter very much to know if it's actually as good, you know?
Yeah.
I need to, I guess, try that again with the crafter.
It's a bucket.
And it goes in here.
Yeah, because...
Output here.
Okay, yeah.
Shared inputs...
Created with the wrench at the back can also reach across covered crafters.
Don't know what that means.
Reach across...
Oh, so it...
I see.
Maybe.
So this is now shared, or...
Okay.
No more?
That seems really weird and complicated.
Let me see the crafter.
Okay, so check it out.
The cra...
Hmm.
I need to make this again.
I need to understand why this...
I mean, obviously this has to be better than that.
Otherwise, what's the point?
Right?
Like, obviously this is limited in some way.
That I don't understand.
Um...
Also, you know what?
Let's just keep going.
Let's unlock some more stuff.
So we got this.
This is kinda cool.
I like it.
Very deep and complicated.
Let's see what else there is.
Okay.
I don't wanna miss anything here.
This I made already.
Threshold switch?
I'm not sure I made this.
Let me just double check my items.
Optical sensor...
I did make it!
Okay.
Good thing I checked.
Fluid valve...
I have not made this actually.
Maybe making this will unlock a bunch of new shit.
Let's just make one.
Electron tube, brass ingot, dried kelp.
Uh...
Don't I have any kelp left?
I do.
Let's just smoke this.
Smoke that!
Then we needed an electron thingy.
Just one.
And it was a brass something, I think?
Just a brass ingot.
You got it!
Brass funnel.
I mean, I think we know what it does, right?
But let's just look at it anyway.
Andesite funnels can only ever extract single items.
Yeah.
This one can do stacks.
And you can set the setting on it to have a specific stack size.
Yeah.
Using items on the filter slot will restrict the funnel to only transfer matching stacks.
Yep.
Wait!
Uh...
This one doesn't have a filter then.
Because I tried that on the andesite funnel.
It didn't work.
Now, it could just be a skill issue.
Maybe I missed the button or the location, you know?
But it doesn't look like there's like a little slot for it similar to here.
You see that?
Using funnels.
I mean, I think this is the same as with the andesite one.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now we have it.
Next up.
What do we got?
Secondary linear chassis.
Okay.
Let's try to make that.
I have a linear chassis some...
Uh...
Chassis.
Sorry.
Linear chassis.
That's how you say that.
There's one.
Secondary.
Okay.
I guess we can turn that into a...
Primary again.
What is the point of these anyway?
Linear chassis.
Connect to identical chassis blocks next to them.
Okay.
Whoop-de-fucking-do.
What's the big deal?
When one is moved by a contraption, the others are dragged with it.
But how is that different?
From just gluing them?
Is it just a way to do it without glue?
Doesn't seem that good.
Chassis of a different type or facing another direction will not attach.
Okay, so secondary and primary will not gel.
Attaching blocks using linear chassis.
Okay.
The open faces of a linear chassis can be made sticky.
Right.
Click again to make the opposite side sticky.
But hold on a minute.
If the whole selling point of the chassis is that it connects, no problem, why would you want to make it sticky?
Maybe to put on something else that is not a chassis?
I guess.
Sneak will remove it.
Yeah.
Sticky faces of the linear chassis will attach a line of blocks.
Hold on, I need to see that again.
Line of blocks in front of it.
So without having to glue it, if it's the same type maybe?
Or just any type of blocks.
Using a wrench, a precise range can be specified for this chassis.
Oh.
So I guess it is just a way to do it without glue.
Holding control adjusts the range of all connected chassis blocks.
Okay.
Honestly, at this point, not super exciting.
But I'm sure I will eat those words later.
When I finally, for some reason, really do need a linear chassis for something.
But we'll see.
I predict it's not going to happen, but who knows.
Schematic table.
Now this sounds kind of cool.
We have to make this.
Two smooth stones.
I have exactly that.
Schematic.
And slabs, of course.
Let's try this one.
Oh, no way!
I get to save contraptions.
Like my digging machine or something.
I can open folder on my computer, I guess.
Wait.
That means you can probably share them between people.
That's actually kind of cool.
Huh.
Alright.
Very nice.
What's next?
Clockwork?
Bearing?
Hold on.
It requires an electron tube.
Let me see if I have that already.
I don't think I do.
We should make it.
Clockwork.
Clockwork bearing.
Give me an electron tube.
Clock.
Ah, clock.
Brass casing and a slab.
I got some slabs.
I got some brass.
I got some...
Oak.
Let's just keep this oak.
In fact, I'm going to make a couple of these.
Since it seems like I need these at some point for things.
Honestly, it looks kind of nice.
Maybe I'll make one of the rooms out of this floor.
This is a nice looking floor, too.
In fact, it kind of fits the dark oak, doesn't it?
Clockwork bearing.
Let's ponder it.
Clockwork bearings attached to blocks in front of them.
Upon receiving rotational force, the structure will be rotated according to the hour of the day.
What?
Like a daylight sensor.
Almost.
Or is it like...
Oh, is it every hour?
Three o'clock, it's pointing to the right?
One, two, three, four...
Oh, that's cool.
That is really neat.
Wait, that means I can make a giant clock!
Right-click the bearing to start or stop animating the structure.
This is so frickin' cool.
Big fan of this.
With the help of superglue, larger structures can be moved.
Yeah, I can make my own clock.
And I will do it.
And then, when it reaches 12, I'm gonna make it go ding, ding, ding.
In front of the hour hand, a second structure can be added.
Is that the seconds?
Or sorry, minutes.
Show me.
No way!
Ensure that the two structures are not glued to each other.
That is frickin' awesome!
Guys...
This is amazing.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Like, there's no real need to have that, but it's cool that it's there, you know?
I mean, maybe there is a mechanism you can utilize this for, other than just making a giant badass clock.
But even if there's no use case out of that, or outside of that, I'm totally happy, you know?
This is great.
Okay!
Let's see what else we can make.
Where was I?
Oh!
Here.
Contraption controls!
I didn't do this!
I bet I need this for a train!
Let's make this.
We need a button, and a side casing, and an electron tube.
I used all my tubes now!
How do I make a button?
Oh, that's super easy.
Uh, controls...
And the side...
I have a lot of those.
Oh, this surely will show me something.
Actors on moving contraptions are always active by default.
Contraption controls can be used to toggle them on the fly.
Oh, shit!
I can put this on my digging machine!
And start and stop it at...
Oh, no way.
They can be attached anywhere on the contraption.
Yes?
Dude, I'm starting to understand all of this.
While disassembled, the filter can be changed to target specific types of actors.
Oh!
Oh, that's cool!
So you can control the drill independently from...
This thing!
If it is a redstone activated during assembly...
If it is redstone activated during assembly...
Then what?
Targeted actors will be turned off from the start.
Okay.
Very cool!
This definitely needs to go inside of here now.
This is part of my digging machine.
And obviously this will be used to control a train, right?
It's only logical.
Steam engine, I think we need this for a train.
But I already made it.
We can try the andeside propeller, although I think we don't need that for a train.
Tires?
We don't need that for a train.
At least not out of rubber.
Mechanical drill...
Weighted ejector!
Hey, we have a bunch of depots that we don't use for anything.
Golden sheet, depot, cogwheel.
Okay.
Uh, depot...
Ah, there we go.
Golden sheet...
Is that golden?
No, that's brass.
Let's go press them!
And I think all my cogs...
Are at the factory.
Oh, right.
I'm so used to going to this spot.
I've been conditioned.
There you go.
Press those.
Um...
Didn't I also bring back a bunch of gold?
Where did all that gold go?
I just need two of these right now?
Or just one, actually?
Oh!
64 copper sheets!
Nice!
Oh, by the way, I think I should make it so that I can listen to the creative sounds or creative music in the normal gameplay.
I did that once.
And I think in season two, but we never really got to listen to a lot of the tracks, but I really want to try to listen to all those tracks, you know?
Look at all these underside casings!
Fuck!
That's awesome!
That's so many!
Industrialization rocks!
It is amazing.
Wow.
In fact, I'll take some wheels and stuff to bring with me here.
Because we don't need this stuff here, I don't think.
Not all of it, at least.
Or anyway.
Charcoal...
Let's take some...
Uh...
Basin...
Yeah, it's fine.
I'm happy.
The factory life is the life for me.
I love approaching from this angle, because look!
These windows and the little porch...
We need a path that goes from here to the factory.
I hear skeletons!
Let's go to bed!
You are not coming in!
Not allowed!
Ah, burn in hell.
Bastards.
Dun, dun, dun...
Let me, uh, actually grab some of these and hold on to it.
I forgot what I was making now.
I think it was...
This one.
Weighted ejector.
Ponder on it!
Sneak and right-click holding an ejector to select its target location?!
No way!
We're doing Quake-style jumps?!
That's what I'm imagining.
Please be right.
The placed ejector will now launch objects to the marked location!
A valid target can be at any height or distance within range.
Wait, what is range?
They cannot, however, be off to a side.
Okay, makes sense.
If no valid target was selected, it will simply target the block directly in front.
Right, okay.
Supply rotational force in order to make it work.
Items placed on the ejector cause it to trigger.
Okay.
What about players?
Can I use it?
Myself?
If inventories are targeted, the ejector will wait until there is space.
Oh, that's really smart.
Using the value panel, a required stack size can be configured- Wow!
Wait, this is like- Hold up.
Who needs belts?!
Fuck belts!
We're going with ejectors!
I guess sometimes you'd need a belt.
There's a belt.
It is now limited to this stack size and only activates when its health stack reaches its- That's so cool, dude.
Oh my goodness.
I will never use belts again, guys.
I think it can be done without belts.
We don't need belts, we can just eject to there, to there.
Haha, yeah.
Mobs and players will always trigger an ejector when stepping on it.
Nice!
Combined with brass tunnels, ejectors can split item stacks by specific amounts.
What the fuck?
That's very complicated now.
What a weird specific interaction.
First, configure the brass tunnel to prefer nearest in order to prioritize its side output.
Dude, what?
Maybe calm down a bit here.
The stack size set on the ejector now determines the amount to be split off.
Okay, dude.
I'm not going to be using this in the foreseeable future.
While a new stack of the configured size exits the side output, the remainder will continue on its path.
Oh.
Oh, that's...
Oh, hold on.
That's actually really useful.
Because let's say I bring in the wood of a certain stack size, right, that I have in my factory.
And yes, I want to use the wood to make andeside casings.
But let's say I also want to use it to make brass casings, so I split half of it off in one direction.
Right?
And that goes on to do other things with it.
Very cool.
Oh!
Yes!
When powered by redstone, ejectors will not activate.
An observer.
Observers can detect when ejectors activate.
Okay, and send a pulse.
Nice.
Okay, guys, I will make...
An orphan slingshotter.
We will be slingshotting the orphans into a pit of death.
It's going to be glorious.
Haha!
Let's try this, shall we?
Oh, wait, what?
Ah!
Wait, step into my office!
Why won't it, um...
Fuck.
I don't understand why I...
What
the...
I can't select...
It's like it's activated already somehow.
Dude, I don't fucking get this.
It seemed pretty simple in the ponder.
What am I not understanding?
Oh!
Sneak right click!
This shit makes no sense.
Wait.
Let me see this.
Oh!
Holding an...
That's the maximum range!
Ejecting to...
Okay.
Too much information.
Honestly.
So why are you not ejecting?
Let's read about it again.
No idea where that is.
I wonder if it's saved now, the output.
Yes.
Yep.
Oh, it needs to be charged up.
Okay!
We gotta crank that shit, in other words!
It's probably not linked anymore.
So let's just redo that.
In fact, let's do it here.
Toolbox...
Oh, shit!
That takes a while!
I guess you need to...
I wonder if this is, um...
Proportional to the distance you set the target at.
If it's closer, maybe it doesn't take as long to charge it.
I wonder if I can die from this!
Like, let's say I fly way high up and then fall down.
What do you think of that, cow?
Did you like that?
What's up, cow?
Moo!
You're dead now.
I wanna launch a cow so bad.
But, we cannot be distracted.
While the ejector is amazing...
We have an ultimate plan right now.
Which is making the train.
We're going to make a train.
No distractions.
This golden helmet can...
Burn in hell.
Good.
And it's gone.
Look!
Smart.
Cook that beef.
Let's see what else we can make.
I think I went too far.
Where was I?
I made the ejecting thingy.
This one.
Okay, let's keep going.
We can make a block of brass.
I haven't done that yet.
Steam whistle.
Copper and golden sheet.
That's easy.
And brass, I guess.
Maybe I did already make that.
Steam whistle.
Ho!
Oh yeah, I guess when steam reaches it, it's gonna whistle.
Steam whistles can be placed on a fluid tank.
Yeah, and when you...
Yeah, okay.
If the tank receives sufficient heat, it's gonna go beep.
A lever.
The whistle will play a note when activated.
Okay.
It looks like a face!
Opening.
Use a whistle item on the block to lower its pitch.
Oh!
Cycle between three different octaves using a wrench.
Oh my god.
I don't know music theory.
I know what pitch is, that's it.
Engineer's goggles can help to find out the current pitch.
Okay.
Sweet.
We gotta try and put that on the current steam engine over there, just to see.
Very nice.
Did I make a chain conveyor yet?
Don't think so.
Let's make one.
Oh my god.
So many new discoveries.
Let's have a look.
Right click two conveyors with chains.
That is so cool!
Tell me I can write those.
With a wrench, maybe?
Wait, what?
Chain conveyors relay rotational power between each other.
Oh!
No more infinite rods!
Very cool.
And connect the shafts above or below them.
Nice!
Can I go up?
With it?
Right click holding a wrench to start traveling on the chain!
Cheers to that.
This is how I'm gonna...
Dude, this is Death Stranding!
Almost.
This is strand type gameplay.
At a junction faced towards a chain to follow it.
Sweet!
Kinda looks like those things on ski resorts, you know?
I wonder, though, if I can go at an elevation with it.
This is the big test we need to make.
Oh, wait!
It already shows that!
Look!
It's because of the perspective.
It looked like, to me, they were at the same height.
You see that?
I was so confused for a second.
So you can definitely go up and down.
Nice!
Okay!
Put that in there.
Haha!
We got more stuff to experiment with.
I actually unlocked so many things, I almost forgot that I had so many new things to look at.
Velocity sensor.
Could be an idea.
But it doesn't seem that pressing, does it?
Gantry shed.
We can try that.
Redstone dust and two anti-site.
Oh, I don't have any on me, I don't think.
I have some.
Gantry.
And redstone dust.
I got it.
Let's see that.
Oh, okay, yeah.
Gantry shafts form the basis of a gantry setup.
Attached carriages will move along them.
Man, this is so deep.
You can do so many things.
Gantry setups can move attached blocks.
You can literally make a Tetris game.
With the help of superglue, larger structures can be moved.
You can stop it at a certain point.
Okay, yeah, okay.
Redstone powered gantry shafts stop moving their carriages.
Instead, its rotational force is related to the carriage's output shaft.
Wait, you can do like this and then transport them this way suddenly?
By the way, you know what this is?
This is a horizontal elevator.
I guess it's not an elevator, it's a translator in that case.
Gantry shafts can have opposite orientations.
The movement direction of carriages depend on their...
But they look to me like they are...
Huh?
This doesn't make sense to me.
You can bring things together?
Wait, no fucking way.
We can bring these together and then they interact these cogwheels?
Show me that they're...
Okay, maybe not.
Gantry shafts attached to a carriage without...
Hold on, it's too fast.
Attached to a carriage without the need of superglue.
Right, okay.
Oh my god, wait.
This is like...
Same applies for carriages on moved gantry shafts.
You know what we need now?
We need a little tube down below that sprays out a little bit of cement.
Thus, a gantry system can be cascaded to cover multiple axes of movement.
Yeah.
We can actually make a printer.
I'm gonna make a 3D printed house.
In fact, I'm gonna write it down.
3D printed house.
With cement.
Wouldn't even surprise me if cement is a real thing in this.
Okay.
Guys, I gotta go take a piss real bad.
I don't know.
This is going right through me.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Let's continue.
I was at...
We're on this page.
That was the gantry shaft.
Smart chute, I think we know what that does.
Don't need to make it.
Now, tires...
Uh...
Like, I'm imagining...
If we can make a train, it would have to be wheels made of metal.
You know, that go along metal rails.
And I wonder if it's just the rails that end up being the thing for that.
As we'll have to see.
Attribute filter.
What is this?
Matches items against a set of attributes or categories.
Can be used in filter slots of creates components.
Oh, so you put this inside the filter slot of a component.
And you can now...
Do it a little more...
What do you call it?
You can be more granular in your filtering.
More precise.
As in, I only want...
Well, what's an example?
I don't have an example off the top of my head.
But you know what I mean.
Activator rail.
List filter.
Matches items against a collection of items or other filters.
Can be used in...
Okay.
Well, we gotta make these and try to experiment with that.
But this doesn't seem like the train.
This is definitely train thingy, isn't it?
Throttle lever.
Metal bracket.
Gantry carriage.
Sticker.
I made this already.
Altitude.
Steering wheel not needed.
Nozzle not needed.
I mean, we already...
Torsion spring could maybe be it?
I don't know.
Sounds...
Plausible.
Spring shaft and the side casing.
Spring.
And a shaft.
Wait, what is a shaft?
Oh, this is...
Right.
For some reason, in my mind, they were called rods.
And the side casing.
We have it.
Okay.
What is this?
Torsion springs.
Relay rotation within a set range of angles.
Alright.
Oh, so you can stop it from rotating all the way around.
When the input stops rotating, the spring returns to its starting angle.
Because it's a spring.
Makes sense.
Snap back to reality.
The angle limit can be configured.
Okay, okay, okay.
Yeah.
I'm not even feeling overloaded with information right now, even though I'm unlocking all this.
I'm totally fine.
Mind that bearings have to be specifically told not to disassemble.
I will mind that.
Right before I forget it.
Stop the rotation.
Oh, they will not spring back.
Okay.
Very nice.
Aha!
Redstone comparators can be used to read the current angle of the spring.
150.
Cool.
Alrighty.
I'm not sure where I would use something like that.
I'm trying to think.
Yeah, I'm not sure.
Maybe with like...
With an airplane and you have the fin in the back or whatever, the one that determines your yaw.
You know?
I guess that is one example.
Okay, let me keep going here.
Flywheel.
Let's make that...
I think I already made one of those actually.
Never mind.
Steering wheel.
Encased chain drive.
Physics.
These are new, I think.
Encased chain drive.
Do I have that?
I feel like that's familiar.
Nope.
Let's make both.
Hey, why are there two?
Oh, okay.
You can do both.
Oh, that's an easy one.
Nuggets and casing.
I got it.
Oh, I guess this is for a chain.
Well, let me see it anyway.
Oh, we unlocked new stuff.
Chain drives relay rotation to each other in a ro...
Wait a minute!
Didn't I see this in the first world we made?
Oh my god!
This would have been so nice with the belts!
That's what I need, baby!
Oh, wow.
Wow!
I'm so happy.
All shafts connected like this will rotate in the same direction!
Yes!
That's so great!
Very nice!
And it's so cheap to make too!
And look at this!
You can go up now too?
Any part of the row can be rotated?
That's crazy.
Unpowered chain gear shifts behave exactly like chain drives.
So if you...
Yeah, and then it...
Uh...
Goes the other way?
Source 16 RPM.
Okay, so if you activate it, what then?
Wait, hold on!
Go back!
Show me again!
So they come down.
It's rotating that way.
Okay.
And now...
Wait, what?
When powered, the speed transmitted to other chain drives in the row is doubled.
Oh!
Whoa!
No way!
This is like an ultra-compact way of increasing speed.
I guess it's gonna slow it.
Whenever the powered gear shift is not at the source, its speed will be halved instead.
Yeah, okay.
Sick.
Oh, so if I were to put it here, it would be 8, and this one would also be 8.
In both cases, chain drives in the row always run at 2x the speed of the powered gear shift.
Oh, okay.
I see.
But I'm gonna forget that.
Using analog signals, the ratio can be adjusted more precisely between 1 and 2.
Whoa!
I thought it was always just 1 and 2.
Ah, okay.
1 third?
Or 2 thirds, I guess.
That's cool, man!
This seems insanely useful.
This is a real nice boy right here.
In fact, you're so nice, you get a special slot right there.
So I will never forget you.
Why did that just...
Was that the first time I've been able to make that?
Okay, where was I?
Physics assembler.
Two alloys, casing, lever.
And I don't have a lever.
Yes, I do.
Lever.
Oh, here we go!
Unlocked a bunch of new shit!
Let's see.
The physics assembler assembles blocks into simulated contraptions.
Use super glue or honey glue to select a group of blocks.
So wait, my current glue is not enough?
This is yellow and not green.
Yes, what happens?
Then hold right click and pull the lever to assemble...
Huh?
Oh, because it's...
It's not even.
Note that blocks along diagonal edges are included.
Whoa, okay.
That's...
How do you even make that though?
I guess you have to place...
Temporary blocks?
What is the point of this though?
Once assembled, the original physics assembler is no longer needed.
How do you make it not physics then?
And any physics assembler can be used...
Oh, so you can just put it on even though it's not straight?
Hmm...
It writes itself?
Dude, what...
This thing falling over breaks my brain.
This is so counter Minecraft...
In my mind.
What?
Wait, really?
I can do that?
Oh my god!
They stole my idea!
This was my idea!
Remember?
I said this.
I said fan.
I said something else.
And then...
Okay.
Wait, are you taking the eyes with you?
Or is this supposed to be understood as there's eyes underneath?
Because I guess, you know...
You can't tell whether or not...
Something else is moving or you're moving.
You know, if the eyes is above or below, it doesn't really matter.
It's all relative.
That looks crazy!
What?
You can make that?
Dude!
Show me the train now!
I can make a tank!
Wait, what is happening right now?
You can use the actual belts as belts?
Like, for a vehicle.
Simulated contraptions have physics and remain completely interactable when assembled.
What the fuck?
Some blocks may have different weights.
Oh, I see!
Okay.
Yeah, I see where this is going.
Yeah.
But steel is heavier than feathers?
Oh!
Wait, no way, dude!
You can make some crazy shit with this!
Detailed property information can be...
Okay, yeah, once again.
Goggles, dude.
It floats as well?
No way.
Disconnected sections of simulated contraptions will...
This is breaking my brain.
Dude, the physics assembler!
Is like Pandora's box.
Crazy.
Oh my god.
A slime ball can be used to merge any two simulated contraptions.
Uh-huh.
Really?
Wait, wait, hold on.
What prevents me from making a windmill?
Attaching myself to a string...
And yeeting myself across the floor.
Can I not do that?
There's no way that works.
I refuse to believe it.
My brain will not accept this.
I have to see it for myself.
I need to see this in action.
This right now is a lie.
It's not real.
I don't believe it.
This is all...
It's just animated.
It's not real.
There's no way that works.
I don't believe that.
Okay, we're getting closer to a train.
Weirdly enough, they showed me everything!
Except the train.
Show me the train, dammit!
All that is cool, but I want a train right now.
But I guess maybe that is implied that I can make a train with that.
Let's just keep unlocking things before we play around with it.
What else is new?
Wheel mount?
That sounds like it should be a train thing, right?
Spring iron sheet.
Don't tell me I made it already.
I may have made it already.
Or not.
Oh, I can't ponder it.
Okay.
Mounts wheel-like items to allow for ground travel.
When powered from the top, brakes the attached wheel, increasing friction.
When powered from the side, steers the wheel toward the side the signal is from.
Okay, so that's definitely a car thing.
That's a car right there, but it's not a train.
Because a train doesn't have to rotate its wheels.
Well...
A little, it does have to.
But that's automatic.
According to the tracks, right?
Dude, I'm getting overexcited right now.
This is crazy.
What's next?
A desk bell, maybe.
And a side tunnel.
Package filter.
Dude, show me, like...
Train.
Analog transmission?
Potentially sounds like a train?
I'm not sure.
Oh my god.
Okay, you know what?
Let's just try...
Play around with the things we have now.
I need to try this immediately.
Oh!
Right!
We need glue!
Glue!
Super glue!
Why is this one not...
Oh, maybe it is actually.
Wait a second.
What was the deal?
Yes?
Use super glue or honey glue.
Oh, wait.
Is that the problem?
No?
I have super glue.
Wait, is it...
Do I need to do something extra?
Okay.
Hold, right click, and pull...
Oh, pull the lever!
But is that not what I did?
Oh!
I think it's because I didn't go all the way up.
Because it's technically...
I see, I see.
I think I understand.
Wait a minute.
If I do this...
No way!
That is way too smooth.
That is so slick!
Look at me pushing it!
What?
This is so weird!
What the...
How does this...
Dude, this is so well done!
Holy crap, man!
That is amazing!
Wow!
I am like...
So impressed right now!
I don't believe that's real!
That's insane how well that works!
No freaking way!
Bees, I'm sorry!
Sorry!
Wait, are you still...
Oh, shit!
What?
Get simulated, nerd!
I can't simulate him?
I wanna...
Throw him across the floor!
Oh, shit!
Come here!
I will simulate your ass!
Uh, how do I make it non-simulated?
Is it, uh...
Oh, I need to do this, I guess.
We're back!
I think...
I don't wanna destroy it!
No!
It's still simulated!
I think I need to unglue it!
Oh, shit!
Okay, now...
Uh, wait.
Huh?
This contraption was unable to...
To assemble.
Could not align simulated contraption to disassemble.
What the...
What do you mean?
It's...
No, it's still simulated.
I can't get it all the way up, it seems.
Oops!
I didn't mean to!
I'm sorry, bees!
Oh, no!
My bee home!
I ruined it!
Dude...
Wait a minute...
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
I...
I can't...
Dude, the physics assembler is...
NUTS!
This is unbelievable!
Okay, you know what I think?
I think...
In order to make a train...
We need certain components that we don't have.
How do we get new components?
We make random shit.
Right?
We're gonna make some...
We're gonna make all kinds of stuff now.
Something that is related to a train.
I don't know what's related...
I guess iron.
What's this?
Nameplate.
Did I...
I...
I already made this.
What have I not made?
Uh...
Hold on.
Did I make this?
Oh!
It's showing me I can use these!
Nine of them.
Because three, three, three, right?
Or I can also do this.
I can pack them.
That's cool.
Right!
Maybe we should try this actually.
The...
Mechanical Crafter.
But we need more of them.
Oh my god.
I'm totally overwhelmed right now.
I don't know what to do first.
I'm so excited by everything.
I really wanna do more with this right now.
But I feel like...
I'm gonna save this.
I'm gonna save the physics assembler!
To make a train.
That's gonna be the first real thing I make with this.
Cause I don't wanna just try to...
Physics everything right now.
It's gonna break my brain.
We saved this for the train.
Um...
Let's just look at some recipes here.
Cause there's also stuff from here.
That I can't make normally, right?
Cause you can press things and all that.
Like this, you know?
We can make cardboard leggings, I guess.
But I guess that's not related to a train.
Maybe controller rail!
Did I make that already?
Controller rail?
I'm not sure I made that, but it requires tubes.
And that's kinda in short supply these days.
A bar of chocolate!
I definitely wanna make chocolate.
Dude, Willy Wonka time.
We have the factory, we just need Willy.
Did I make a copper casing?
Let's do that.
Um... wood.
Dun, dun, dun, dun.
Tha, dun, dun, dun.
And now?
Copper.
Oh!
The Copper Age is upon us!
Which reminds me...
Oh!
That's new!
We got new stuff?!
I need to look at the achievements.
I barely looked at this cause, Y'know, there's so much to do even without looking at this.
Get launched more than 30 blocks.
We did this now.
Extend a rope pulley over 200 blocks.
Oh, so you can totally do what I was planning to do.
We just need to make the rope pulley.
Wait.
That's a rope pulley right there.
Right.
We probably need to crank it to do that.
We can't just...
grab it and fall down unless we physics it.
Maybe that is possible then.
Pick up a minecart contraption with at least 200 attached blocks.
Oh!
So this is like...
alluding to the...
outrageous idea that you can transport infinite items.
You know?
It's not lost on them.
Use a mechanical press and a basin to create fewer items from more.
I haven't done that yet.
Is there anything about trains in here?
Create a minecart contraption that places tracks in front of itself?
Operate a pair of crushing wheels at maximum strength?
Obtain a bucket of molten chocolate?
Molten chocolate?
What's the difference between that and melted chocolate?
Is it just hotter?
Oh, it would be in here, wouldn't it?
Swivel bearing.
Connect a rope connector, a rope spool with rope?
Craft a plunger launcher?
What the hell is that?
Inspect a contraption diagram.
Obtain a gyroscopic mechanism.
Place in power a portable engine!
I want that!
Yes!
Gyros...
Hold on.
Gyroscopic mechanism.
Can I make stuff like that?
Oh my god, I can.
Oh!
Dude, let's...
Let's try this!
So, deploy cogwheel.
Deploy shaft.
Oh, it's like...
Okay, so you have the cogwheel.
We shaft on the cogwheel, and then we shaft the little brass noggin on top.
Only 90% chance of a gyroscopic mechanism.
Okay.
Hold on, I need to see what else is there.
Or there is.
Whoa, what?
Oh, I see the point of the crafter!
You can...
We can make things that are bigger than 3x3!
We need 21 of them!
To make a crushing wheel.
Docking connector?
Look at this!
This is like, totally not...
Normal.
Like, it's bigger than 3x3.
This breaks my brain again.
Automated shaped crafting.
Oh, this is just...
This is just everything I can do with a normal crafting table, I guess.
Mechanical crafting.
Okay.
Well, we gotta make some mechanical crafting here.
Crafters.
Dude, I'm looking at this and thinking train.
Doesn't this kind of look like a train, uh...
You know, where the wheel would attach a little bit?
Or maybe a roller coaster, you know?
Dude, can we make a roller coaster?
I wanna make that.
Precision mechanism.
Cockwheel.
Large cockwheel and iron nugget.
Only 80% chance for this one.
I wonder what random salvage is.
Is this gonna be a random block or something?
Repeat sequence five times.
So you have to make a...
Uh...
Like an assembly line.
Where this needs to happen...
Can we not just go in a circle?
I guess we can, right?
Power toggle latch.
Let's see what else there is.
Dude, I should try and make this.
This probably, uh...
Is being used in some recipe in Create.
I can see that being a thing.
Did I even make one fishing rod?
I have yet to fish...
In this world at all.
This I need to go collect.
I think that's gonna be important somehow.
I guess we can make some paintings for a house.
Not a bad idea.
Tires.
But what about the metal tires?
Also called wheels.
Can I not make some wheels?
Oh, wait!
This is probably what we need!
Engine assembly!
Right?
Iron sheet.
Cut it with a saw and...
Process and press.
It's gotta be.
Oh, but then again...
Steam engine is more train-y, isn't it?
Auger shaft.
And this could also be the one.
I'm just gonna take a look here.
Actually, I kinda want to just start simple, because I'm getting overwhelmed.
I wanna make some paintings for my house.
What does it take to make a painting?
Sticks and wool.
Easy.
Let's just calm down a bit, because things have gotten a little crazy lately with the Create stuff here.
Let's put this inside.
All the crazy stuff here.
Wool.
Let's just make, like, ten.
Oh, wait a minute.
That's new.
Stop climbing.
Let's make it.
I know I'm being distracted.
I know.
Just calm down.
Oh, copper casing.
I got that.
Spout.
Oh, oh, oh!
Oh, my God!
What the hell was that?
The spout can fill fluid-holding items provided beneath it.
The content of a spout cannot be accessed manually.
Oh, and you pipe it in.
Instead, pipes can be used to supply it with fluids.
Alright.
Tell me more, fam.
The input items can be placed on a depot under the spout.
Okay.
I mean, the first thought that pops into my mind is brewing, but...
When items are provided on a belt?
I guess it's gonna wait.
Yeah.
Okay.
Wait.
We're gonna make a Worcestershire sauce factory!
We're gonna produce bottles!
I can't say Worcestershire?
Worcestershire.
I can't say it.
That's fucking crazy.
Ha ha ha ha!
Ho ho ho!
Yo!
I love that!
That is sick!
We're gonna automate bees!
In fact, we're gonna hold bees in place along an assembly line and squeeze them until the, you know, the honey comes out.
And we're gonna squeeze it into a bottle.
Ha ha ha ha!
Oh, we haven't even made this, dude!
This is gonna unlock something.
Trust.
Watch this.
I also need a compass anyway.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Look at that!
I've seen that in the animations.
Uh, what is that, a map?
Speedometer!
Okay.
You got it!
Speedo!
Show me some new things.
Wait.
That doesn't...
That looks like the same.
Unless I'm losing my mind.
Crafting blueprint.
Placed on a wall, it can be used to specify ingredient arrangements for easier manual crafting.
Each slot represents a recipe.
Wait.
Say what?
Wait a second.
I am being...
I know I'm being distracted.
It's on purpose, okay?
I'm just...
I'm just taking it all in right now.
I'm letting it wash over me.
Stressometer!
Oh, you can...
I guess you can turn them back and forth, or...
Or not?
I guess this is a way to measure...
Uh, when your shit is gonna break.
I don't wanna ponder it yet.
Yeah, we can turn it back, see?
We can go back and forth.
Let's make this...
Okay, that's big.
Yeah, it's like crafting, so...
But what is the point here?
Like...
Oh!
Oh, that's...
Okay, that's pretty...
That's really cool.
So basically what this is, if you didn't get it...
You basically pre-arrange something so that whenever you need something specific, you go over there and you right-click it.
That's really dope.
Oh, you can have multiple in one!
Oh!
Even better, look!
Oh, wait.
That's a bad idea.
Let's do...
I don't even...
What's a good example?
Yeah, maybe this one.
Secondary display...
Is that like to just have a...
Oh, cool!
Look!
Oh, my God.
Okay, this is amazing.
The most commonly crafted things!
We are gonna have a room dedicated to this.
The ceiling.
The walls.
The floor.
We walk in there and we go like...
Blup, blup, blup, blup, blup, blup.
Depending on what we need.
Amazing.
Let's write it down.
Crafting.
Blueprints.
Room.
Walls.
Roof.
Floor.
Blue.
It's going to be so blue in there.
I may even use blue blocks.
To really emphasize how blue it is.
It's so fitting.
The blue book.
Anyway, I got distracted.
I was doing something.
Oh, yeah.
I was putting up paintings.
Let's do that.
We shall have a painting room.
This is the painting room.
Wait, what is that?
Oh, it's like a temple.
This looks like something out of Dark Souls, too.
Doesn't it?
The area with all the water and...
You know, you walk in...
And there's this boss fight in a circular arena.
You can fall down and stuff.
Looks like it a little bit.
No, that's ugly.
Ew!
Why is it so big?
Stop being big!
That's better.
Can we have a different one?
Okay.
This is the painting room.
Wonderful.
Oh, there's more.
Yeah, I like that one.
A woman is planting a...
Demon seed.
And the demon seed is growing to be quite fearsome.
Not sure what's happening there.
Looks like a little doll or...
Effigy.
I'm thinking of Dark Souls, too, all the time.
Man, what a game.
I need to replay that.
I need to replay Dark Souls 1 and 2.
And now that I have a TV, man...
On the couch.
Definitely.
Birch locks.
They belong in the chest.
Let's just clean up a little bit here.
It's getting ugly.
Almost 30 again.
Whoop!
Stop climbing.
I was crafting random shit, right?
Let's just keep doing that.
What can I make?
Let's make Oakwood.
Doesn't do anything.
Cool.
What else can I make?
What have I not...
We have not made Copper Nuggets, I don't think.
Ah, we probably have.
Turned them back into...
Bars.
Shears we've made.
That we've made.
I've made ladders already.
Dude, which block?
Freaking disenchants my stuff.
I'm losing my mind.
Cauldron I made already.
Chain.
I made it already, I think.
Wooden bracket?
Wait, that was actually kind of cool, right?
We used that to...
Decorate shafts.
Oh yeah, right.
I need to do more of that.
And pipes?
How...
I need to see.
What does it look like?
Also, I just touched my glasses.
Now I have a nice, fat spot of blurriness in my right eye.
And there's no microfiber nearby.
Never mind, there is.
Clean it quick before this guy comes!
Quick, clean it!
I got it!
You, whoa!
Hit me in the ass with that.
Get away from me.
Wanna fight?
Okay, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna mess you up.
Two days of number.
Got him.
Sleep.
Okay, let's actually try this stressometer.
Since we're here at the factory, right?
Here in the garage.
In my factory.
The stressometer displays the current stress capacity of the attached kinetic network.
That's a lot of stress.
When wearing engineer's goggles, the player can get more detailed information from the gauge.
Got it.
I really should be wearing these goggles.
Is what I'm getting from all this.
But maybe I'll not do that.
Comparators can emit analog redstone signals relative to the stressometer's measurements.
Oh.
When would that be useful?
Oh, we're done.
Okay.
Let's put it on.
Stressometer!
We're gonna put it...
Oh, shit.
It's so stressed.
Oh, it's not stressed at all.
Look.
But, if I were to put it over here...
Remember, this one was stressed.
This is gonna be in the red.
You ready?
Come on.
Look at that!
It's at the limit.
The breaking point has been reached, almost.
If a tiny feather...
Or...
A bit of steel...
Were to land on this...
Like that, it would break.
And we know this now because of this.
And we can attach a redstone signal and use that to somehow...
You know...
Yo!
We can even...
A steam whistle, maybe.
Or...
A little...
Dingy-dong.
When the stress is too high, it goes ding-dong!
Dingy-dong!
You know?
Amazing!
Let's use these things we just made.
On pipes!
Dude, that looks amazing!
Oh, yeah!
Hell, yeah!
Let's do one more over here.
We're gonna hold...
Oh, that makes no sense.
That's disgusting.
Where would we want to hold it...
Firm?
Right there!
Oh, yes!
I love that you can do that!
Dude, create is amazing.
I feel like...
It's getting better and better.
The more I play it, you know?
Wild.
Anyway, why did I come here?
I forgot what I was doing.
Let's put a chain down somewhere.
It's a factory, right?
There's chains in factories.
Let's have a chain hanging.
There's a chain hanging right here.
No, that's ugly!
I don't like that.
We should have a chain somewhere.
Why would it make sense to have a train?
Eh, maybe...
I hate...
You know, I hate this fucking...
It doesn't fit anywhere.
I'm going back.
I'm done.
I need to make this train.
I feel like I'm so close to a breakthrough on the train.
I have trouble saying train now that I said chain so much.
Piston extension pole!
We have made that before.
Lightning rod!
We have not made that.
Oh!
We got a hand with a lightning thing in it!
What is that?
Oh yeah!
I forgot about mapping.
Transmitter.
Wait.
Wireless transmitter?
Are you saying redstone wireless?
2.4 gigahertz!
Or 5 gigahertz?
Copper sheet, lightning rod, redstone.
I got it.
Oh wait, I had some already.
Aha!
Wait, what?
Oh, that looks...
That's a lot of stuff!
Please tell me it's wireless redstone.
Stock link.
All right.
Display link?
Directional linked receiver!
Now that's more like it.
Iron sheet brass casing.
I can't even ponder this.
Wait, I don't even have...
I have...
No casing!
Press casing is that one.
Receiver.
Oh, modulating linked receiver.
Gold.
Okay, gold and iron.
Huh.
Let's start with the directional one.
Oh, I think I'm pressing some outside.
Ah, that's gold!
We gotta press some iron now.
Uh, half.
Yeah.
Oh, we already had some.
Damn.
Uh, nope.
I'm so conditioned to go here.
There you go.
You can press that.
Actually, I'm taking one.
Thank you.
That should be it.
Let's make this.
Hold on now.
I think it's exactly what I think it is.
Directional linked receivers can detect the angle to other nearby redstone links.
It's like VOR.
Redstone links directly in front will be received at their full signal strength.
Okay.
I forgot if it's VOR or NDB.
I think NDB is...
Directional beacon...
Ah, I forgot.
A shallower angle results in a lower received signal strength.
Okay.
What is this good for, though?
I guess navigation?
That's what this is.
Directional linked receivers cannot receive signals from redstone links behind them.
How far is the range, though?
Because you can use this to navigate.
You can be like, oh, I'm off axis, you know, and the signal is bad.
I'm gonna go this way.
Directional linked receivers respect the same item frequencies that redstone links use.
Wait, I didn't even know redstone links did that.
I'm not even sure what that is.
I think I can make it.
What is this for, though?
Maybe it's...
Huh.
I guess it's just to transmit information across longer distances.
Wait, I need to see this again here.
Lower received signal strength.
Yeah.
So, like, imagine I put this on a plane that I make.
And I fly around, right?
I'm over here.
Ah, signal strength is 2 out of 10.
Ah, I'm going the wrong way.
Let me go this way.
Oh, 3 out of 10.
4 out of 10.
Okay, okay.
I'm aligning with the correct angle here, you know?
So when I'm here, like, bing, bing, bing, bing.
10 out of 10.
Okay, now I know I need to go north.
And that's how you navigate.
Fun fact.
That's how planes in real life used to do it before.
Or GPS, at least.
But also, of course, the distance between a station and a plane can also be used to measure distances.
Directional link receivers cannot receive signals from rest of the links behind them.
Okay, got it.
The item stuff is intriguing me here.
I just can't see a use case for this.
Right off the bat, at least.
Maybe if you have some kind of factory, I don't know, in Alexandria, you know?
That is producing a bunch of gold bars.
And these are being transported to a factory in Lebanon.
Who knows?
And it needs to know, oh, do we need more gold bars right now?
Or are we good?
Fucking, I don't know.
I'm pulling stuff out of my ass.
Uh, alright.
What else?
Man, this train is...
elusive.
Can I make this yet?
I must have.
Oh, I have one already.
Damn.
We should just craft random stuff, honestly.
We should make one of everything.
I mean, stuff that we obviously haven't made before.
I don't think I've made this.
Or have I?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
Okay, dyes probably is not important.
This is one I made already.
MTMap.
Maybe this...
No.
This is one I made already.
Wait, look in here, actually.
I guess I haven't tried making bricks.
And how do I make normal bricks?
I actually don't know how to make normal bricks.
The hell?
Man, are we actually gonna polish some basalt?
I think the best way to do this...
is to simply empty the inventory first.
Check it out.
This is how we're gonna do it.
Obviously, while still sorting a little bit here.
Okay, and now we just grab a bunch of shit.
A little bit of everything, you know?
And then we see.
What can I make?
Let's polish some deepslate.
Didn't do anything.
Let's do...
Granite.
Tough.
Hey, pressure plate, maybe.
Oh, maybe I should pick them up, actually.
Before it triggers, right?
Oh, look at that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Definitely.
We unlock some new stuff now.
Not bad.
So the lesson here is, don't fill up your inventory all the way.
Just calm down a bit, you know?
You gotta be kidding me!
For real?
That actually looks like it.
There's no way I just hit that like a jackpot.
Please be it.
That's the one that disenchants!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
We're feeding two birds with one scone!
Portable fluid interface?
Whatever.
Wait, what did I just unlock?
Maybe it's over here.
Levitite blend?
Huh?
Builder's tea?
The perfect drink to get the day started motivating and saturating?
Alright.
I don't know how to make that.
Chocolate bucket?
Honey apple?
Yo!
Honey bucket?
I just wanna...
I can't believe we actually did it.
Wow.
Oh, it needs a sequence of...
Recipes...
Oh, okay, okay.
You want me to make factory?
I'll fucking make a factory for this.
You got it.
Iron nuggets, huh?
Deploy it.
We deploy two iron nuggets together.
And...
Process them in a press.
Sick.
Oh, and when...
Oh, okay.
So input is slab.
Ah.
Oh, I see how that works now.
Yo.
This...
You know what?
I declare victory on that one.
Next time it's gonna be train time.
Next time it's train time, baby.
I didn't wanna end before having the train started.
This is the start of the train.
100%.
Right?
Ah, dude.
And we even got the disenchanting thing.
That's just the cherry on top at the end.
Hells yeah.
You know what?
It makes so much sense.
I forgot what I made, but I made some kind of slab.
What are train tracks made of?
Like a piece of stone or metal, you know, like at the bottom?
But it's not a fully sized block.
It's like a slab.
It totally makes sense.
Ah, man.
Tunic.
Yes, it's tunic music.
Such a great game.
It's from a game called Tunic.
It's a puzzle adventure game inspired by Zelda.
Although not exactly like Zelda, but somewhat like it, you know?
It's awesome.
Highly recommended.
Yeah, this stream was nuts.
I discovered so many things.
And it's not like it's a miracle that I did.
It's just that I finally decided to craft all this stuff that was in my crafting book, you know?
Because I let that build up over a long time, and now I finally got to it.
When is next stream?
I don't know.
I'm sorry, but what I can tell you is that when it happens, either I announce it on Discord ahead of time, or I don't.
But if I don't, it's always going to be around 3 p.m.
Central European Standard Time.
If that helps.
But sometimes it can also be earlier or later.
It depends, really.
I was late, don't spoil.
I won't.
You should probably not watch right now, then.
You should get out of here.
Because people will spoil it, what just happened.
It's kind of big, though.
Been watching bots in Season 2.
First time in stream typing.
Hello, Oliver.
Watching you play makes me want to try out Create for myself, and I just made my first Steam engine.
By the way, pondering helps a lot.
Yeah, it does.
Hey, how are you finding it so far?
You like it?
I'm having such a blast with Create.
I must take my hat off to the person or people who made this, because it is so unbelievably polished.
And it feels so Minecraft-y, too, you know?
All the designs of the blocks.
It's just spot-on, you know?
They really nailed it when it comes to the Minecraft aesthetic and design of it.
It's just...
Chef's kiss.
Wonderful.
I don't know if it's a team or if it's one guy.
It doesn't matter.
It's so impressive in any case.
Yeah.
They're so good at adhering to the art style of the game.
Oh, she's trying...
She can already feel somehow.
It's like she knows.
Sorry, I'm talking about my cat now.
Jackie.
But hey, it actually helped having a little bed for her.
She wasn't jumping up on the table.
Could just be a coincidence, though.
Clocktower next stream?
Hmm, no.
Next stream is gonna be Train.
But if we have a train, we almost gotta have a clock as well, right?
To announce arrival times of trains and stuff.
I don't know.
I'm just imagining this clock tower at the train station, right?
No, we're not gonna have a clock town or a clock on a train.
That's that stupid.
Or maybe not.
I don't know.
But we definitely need some kind of schedule.
I can smell the great railway coming.
Yes!
The music is making me want to replay tuning so bad right now.
I feel like it doesn't have a lot of replay value.
Maybe in a couple years for me when I...
When I forget some things.
But it is a vibe just running around in that game for sure.
Oliver, the mod is missing Recipes for Liquids.
The funny...
The good thing about this is...
It's a self-healing process in a way.
Because after every time I stream...
I upload the...
So there's like a text file that is being generated with the mod...
With everything that I discover.
And I upload that to...
The system that I have in place to check for it.
And it'll see whether or not it corresponds with what I should have or not.
So it should self-heal.
It's been working well so far, I guess.
I think you left some very end-game puzzles in Tunic.
I mean, most likely.
Like, while I am a perfectionist...
Or not a perfectionist, like a completionist in some ways...
When it comes to games...
I'm not like an ultra-mega completionist.
You know?
It's not like I will go out of my way to...
Get every single achievement and...
Do absolutely everything.
I basically play until I don't have fun anymore, right?
And if a game is fun...
All the way to the end...
Where you have everything...
Well, that...
Then I go for everything, right?
It's very simple.
I think someone said that the fluids are a special type of thing that's not an item so it doesn't show up.
Okay, that's actually good information.
I'm gonna relay that.
But don't worry, guys.
We're gonna...
We're gonna have...
I mean, there's no rush here.
We're gonna figure things out.
And hold on a minute.
I'm not...
I wouldn't even be surprised if what you're talking about is already working...
Correctly.
And all I need is a spout.
The one I just found.
Because that seems to be related to all that, you know?
So maybe let's not go too crazy yet.
Just...
Trust the process.
I have not played Superliminal.
But I have heard about it.
It's like a small puzzle game similar to stuff like Antichamber.
In terms of scope and design, you know?
Obviously different, but still.
Will you release the mod?
I don't know.
People don't like things made this way.
So I'd rather just not be a target.
I made it for myself to have fun with it.
And I'm having fun with it.
And that's the end of it.
People are weirdly opinionated on things like that.
And I don't want to, you know, stir up shit.
So...
Personal project.
I'm having a blast with it.
That's it.
It was vibe-coded to the extent where...
I still spent probably over 100 hours on it.
If you think all it takes is a single prompt to make this...
You are heavily under an illusion.
That is not how this works.
And I went to great lengths to protect myself from spoilers at the same time.
Obviously I couldn't protect myself all the way.
So that's why I knew some stuff starting it.
But with the tools that are available right now...
It is possible to do things like this while staying spoiler-free.
Which is absolutely insane.
My life will be complete the day you play Abiotic Factor.
One of my favorite games I've ever played.
It's already on my list.
And you know what?
I actually almost considered playing it.
Because I heard someone else...
Some content creator...
I forget the name of them.
But someone mentioned this and it was like an amazing game.
Maybe it was Coke Carnage?
Could that be it?
I think Coke Carnage may have talked about Abiotic Factor.
But it's on my list.
It's definitely a game that's coming up.
At some point.
I mean, I basically knew when I started the mod...
That there was a thing called...
Simulate.
Like, create simulate.
And that you had to use Andeside.
And stuff like that, you know?
But honestly, I'd rather do it like this and be a little spoiled...
Compared to just having a recipe book...
That shows me absolutely everything in the game from day one.
Imagine how overwhelmed...
I of all people would be.
I just don't think it would be...
Very fun for me.
I would honestly look at that and go...
Yeah, I...
I don't know where to start.
I...
I can't.
I can't do this.
You know?
Yeah.
I love your house.
Thank you!
I think it's great too.
Although, I will say...
It needs a little bit more color.
I saw some people...
Say that it's like...
A chocolate house.
And I can see why they say that.
But I feel sort of the same way.
Just so you know.
I am aware that it's very brown.
And I'm thinking of ways to incorporate other colors and...
Styles into it to make it look a little more varied, right?
But yeah, all in all, I'm also very happy with it yet.
Or so far.
And it's not done yet.
There's more to be done.
I have other ideas.
I don't think I've already fixed the chocolate house thing.
They're still...
Inside, it looks a little too chocolatey.
But the floors will make it a lot better.
When I put in the floors.
Next stream went, my lord.
Probably in a day or two.
Most likely in a day.
I think tomorrow I'm gonna hang up stuff.
It's gonna be the hanging up day.
I still haven't hung up any picture frames or...
Jackie's little platforms.
I think I'll do that tomorrow or the day after.
And I'm like so slow when it comes to that.
I don't know.
It can take me a whole day to get that done.
Because I have to measure everything so many times.
And drilling in concrete is a pain in the ass.
So we'll see.
I also don't like drilling in the walls.
Because I'm renting.
And I know I'm allowed to.
I just hate doing it, you know?
Because it's like a pain in the ass to fix later when...
Yeah, I don't know.
Yeah, it's not made of drywall.
It's like...
You need a hammer drill to get through that.
You're mega wealthy, I wish.
Remember to wear gloves on your ears.
I will.
Actually, I never do that.
It's not that loud.
Like, I'll survive.
But maybe you're right.
Maybe I should actually wear air protection.
As someone who works on fixing rented homes, trust me, Oliver.
It's so easy to patch, drill, nail holes.
Okay.
I mean, you're just using the filler, right?
But isn't that, over time, going to make the wall really terrible?
Like, the more renters live there, the wall is going to end up being, like...
...filled with this crap that isn't concrete.
Over time.
I'm also so nervous about hitting something, like an electrical cord or something behind the wall.
Because I don't know.
I know you can buy items that, like, make a little beep.
If there's, like, a stud there or something.
But I don't have that, you know?
And I assume people make houses nowadays where they don't have those important infrastructure stuff right in the center of a wall.
Yeah, I quit my job as a PhD student to go full-time with the streaming.
So far, it's paying off, man.
I can live off of it.
Isn't that crazy?
I meant to say you should mega-wealthy.
Haha, yeah, okay.
I'm just gonna go ahead and become mega-wealthy.
Thank you.
Yeah, I can live off the streaming right now.
Thanks to you guys.
I'm actually not talking to Diego very much nowadays.
He's also on the other side of the world right now, doing a post-doc.
I think he is in...
Oh, let me think.
Is it Chile?
I think it's Chile.
Doing a post-doc there.
Something like that.
Man, I couldn't even imagine being in student debt.
I feel so bad for you guys.
That are going through that.
I'm lucky to be in...
Or have been in the situation where if you study here...
Not only does it cost...
Does it not cost any money to study...
But the government pays you a salary to study.
So it's like...
Uno reverse on that system here.
You know?
It's like...
I'm super...
What do you call it?
Like, it's...
What's the word?
I'm super privileged...
To be able to study...
And get paid for it.
You know?
It's so nice.
Yeah.
But I mean...
I'm paying taxes, right?
So now I'm also helping everyone else.
I'm basically also helping to pay for other people's student.
Or like...
University tuition.
So that's awesome.
I love it.
Yeah, you're no longer a PhD student.
So now you can get bad pills.
You're right.
You mean the false PhD.
I need to get out of this country.
Wait, where do you live, Catharsis?
Maybe I missed your message.
United States?
I mean, that's not a bad country to live in, though.
I mean, yeah, you have to pay for...
Tuition and stuff, right?
But you also don't pay taxes, so...
I mean, there's good and bad with every system.
There's definitely some advantages.
I mean, the US is also kind of awesome, right?
Jackie's now at my...
Table, I think she knows.
Is it time to eat?
Hmm?
Oh my god, she's so cute.
I just want to hug her all the time.
I think I'll never get tired of that.
You know, I see my cat.
I come into the living room and I see her lying on the couch and I just jump over to her.
Tiki!
You know?
She must be so tired of me.
I never get tired of her cuteness.
US gets a bad rap on Reddit and TikTok, but it's truly not a bad place to live.
I bet it's awesome to live there.
Honestly.
All the Americans that I know in real life are some of the coolest people ever.
And when I was in America, I loved the place, man.
Everyone was so nice, you know?
Talking to each other and stuff.
Even though, I mean, I am very Danish.
So maybe it's a little annoying for me when people try to chat me up in the supermarket all the time.
But it's just kind of cool that you guys are like that, you know?
Like, you're so chatty and open and...
Yeah, it's just way more open, I guess.
In Denmark, we're pretty closed off, you know?
When you get on the train in Denmark, people try to avoid eye contact.
They sit with their headphones on.
They just want to be left alone.
But yeah.
What are you posting to about Jackie?
Ah, you're right!
I should record more videos of her.
I just don't know what to record, you know?
Maybe her eating or just doing random things.
Jackie pooping.
Jackie eating.
Jackie sleeping.
Just random stuff.
Maybe not the pooping.
I think she would feel a little...
Not good about me jumping into the bathroom with a camera when she's pooping.
Even cats would feel like I'm violating something there, you know?
That's not good.
I'm American, and I kept having to force myself not to smile at strangers and do small talk with them while abroad.
You should!
The thing is, though, we may act like we don't, you know, want to be talked to, but a lot of times we do, and...
I mean, in the end, we're all just human, you know?
We're all the same, in a way.
It's nice to be smiled at by someone.
It doesn't really matter who it is.
Unless you're having a really shitty day.
So I think you should keep it up.
Just keep doing that.
Japan is the king of not talking in public.
Oh, yeah?
I haven't been there, but I can imagine.
Speaking of Japan, I actually started watching a TV show called Tokyo Vice.
It's quite good.
I recommend.
Really wonderful show so far.
I just finished the first season.
I was in Baltimore in the U.S.
Okay, there is one American person that I did not like very much while I was there.
And that was my Uber driver.
That's the only one.
He was, like, extremely racist.
Like, I got into the cab, and we were driving through these neighborhoods, and he just kept going on and on about certain races.
And I was just like, I've never experienced anyone like this in my life.
So this was just straight out of a movie.
You know?
I was just sitting there saying, yeah, okay.
I didn't want to engage in it, you know?
That was so awkward, man.
I was so happy to get out of that.
Pace driver?
Not really.
I hope this dream never ends.
Okay, I will never end this dream.
But that means Jackie's gonna die of starvation.
So do you want that to happen?
Do you want me to die of starvation?
That's up to you, man.
You wanted to play this game.
Okay, I'm gonna go, guys.
It's not gonna be an infinite stream, but we're gonna have more streams coming, especially now that trains are on the menu.
It's gonna be a good time.
I will see you on the flip side.
Have a good day.
Bye-bye.